-=本字幕由 第三楼字幕网 原创翻译=-
字幕下载站http://www.disanlou.org
字幕仅供翻译学习交流使用 禁止用于商业用途
外挂字幕由 第三楼字幕网 独家首发
转载、内封、压制必须注明字幕来源
那是炸弹爆炸的声音
That was a bomb.
（2006年阿富汗喀布尔）
还不清楚是简易爆炸装置 还是特制的汽车炸弹
No word as to whether it was an IED or a specific car bomb.
伤亡人数超过十人
Over 10 fatalities reported.
来自ISAF的消息称 此事也许和ISI有关
Sources within ISAF suggest that ISI may be involved.
这些电话是打不通 还是那混蛋挂了我的电话？
Did these phones just go down or did that fucker hang up on me?
好在X很狡猾 不然我现在就在飞机上了
Good thing that X was bodgy or I'd be flying right now!
我听不见，亲爱的
I can't hear you, honey.
我找艾德·法伯尔
I need to talk to Ed Faber.
那么是谁在主持？
Well, then who is fronting the show?
我听不清
I can't hear you!
嘿，那是我的屁股
Hey, that's my ass!
你有妈教吗？
Do you have a mother?
别用你的屁股碰我的手
Don't put your ass on my hand!
闭嘴，你这死驴脸
Shut up, donkey pussy!
贱货，公交车
Whore! Dog-washer!
我的老二在你耳朵里
My cock in your ear!
我的老二在你耳朵里 我要戳烂你的臭嘴
My cock in your ear! I shit on your lips!
你吃屎去吧
Eat a fart!
喂
Hello!
该死...
Fu...
（三年前）
（新闻一部制作人：金姆·贝克）
听着，伊拉克战争正在进行
<i>Listen up. Iraq Two is happening.</i>
那里的关系网已经饱和了 我们所有的人才都去了那里
The network is stretched thin. All our talent is going there.
我们需要人手填补 阿富汗的空缺，任何人都行
We need people, any people, to fill the void in Afghanistan.
在座的各位都是本公司
And you folks here are all the unmarried,
未婚且没有孩子的人员
childless personnel in this bureau.
对于那些一直从事幕后工作的人来说
For those of you who are behind the scenes, there are
这是一个走到镜头前的机会
opportunities to be on camera.
金姆，你愿意一起吗？
Kim, are you going to be joining in?
一起去还是一起哭？
The travel or the crying?
希望是一起去
Um, hopefully, the travel.
我会考虑的
I'll think about it.
猫鼬行动的成功进行
<i>The success of Operation Mongoose</i>
让人们忽略了极为重要的一个事实
<i>has overshadowed the real lesson to be learned,</i>
那就是塔利班组织根本未被征服
<i>that the Taliban are far from vanquished.</i>
随着战斗的鼓声
<i>And as the drums of war</i>
（战斗的号角） 在伊拉克愈演愈烈
<i>beat ever louder in Iraq,</i>
北约在阿富汗的任务 变得越来越靠不住
<i>the NATO mission in Afghanistan grows increasingly uncertain.</i>
以上是VBC环球新闻的 谭雅·范德普尔
<i>Tanya Vanderpoel, outside Lashkar Gah, Afghanistan,</i>
从阿富汗拉什卡尔加为您发回的报道
<i>VBC World News.</i>
嘿
Hey.
（爱你，金姆姨妈） 接通了，嘿
I got you! Hey.
你什么时候从休斯顿回来？
Uh, when do you get back from Houston?
我想是周二，问这个干嘛？
<i>I think on Tuesday. Why?</i>
因为我周二要去阿富汗
Uh, because I'm going to Afghanistan on Tuesday.
你周二要去阿富汗？
<i>You're going to Afghanistan on Tuesday?</i>
是的
Yeah.
但你是负责编辑新闻的
<i>But you write news copy.</i>
等等，要去多久？
<i>Wait. For how long?</i>
- 大概三个月 - 什么？
- Like, three months. <i>- What?</i>
金姆
Kim!
嘿
Hey!
真不敢相信这事成了
I can't believe this worked out!
嘿，你想去卫生间的
Hey, you want to have a quickie
可调桌那儿来一发吗？
on the changing table in the bathroom?
那个小树袋熊看着我
Yeah, I don't think I could get it up
我可提不起性趣
with that little koala looking at me.
要开始登记了
Also, they're boarding already.
嘿，别担心，去吧，去吧
Hey, don't worry. Just go. Go, go, go.
对了，我...我给你配了钥匙
Oh, shoot, I... I copied a key for you, so...
浇花，信件
Plants, mail.
- 还有什么需要处理的？ - 我想就那些了
- Anything else I'm forgetting? - I think that's it.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
听着，我觉得这令人骄傲
Listen, I think it's impressive.
开始新的职业生涯？
Starting a new career?
这会很棒的
It's gonna be great.
听着，不到三个月
And listen, in three months...
我就回来了
"I'll be back."
不，那太糟了，不
No, that's terrible! No.
别那样记住我，不
Don't remember me like that. No.
再见，好的，好的
Bye. Okay. Okay.
这不是我的工作，我是个制片人 是安然公司负责新闻的
It's not my job. I'm a producer. General news. Enron.
报道宾夕法尼亚州煤矿工人们的消息
These coalminers in Pennsylvania,
但你也许没看过
but you probably didn't see that.
因为我们在进行两场战争
'Cause we got two wars going on now,
我知道怎么设置局域网
so, uh, I know how to set up a BGAN
我死了也没人会上诉
and no one will sue if I die
所以我两天前办了 一张加快签证
so I got an expedited visa, like, two days ago,
我想现在我是战地记者
and I guess now I'm a war reporter.
真该死
Shit dick!
螺旋形降落
Corkscrew landing.
以免导弹击中飞机
In case a missile is fired at the aircraft!
喀布尔国际机场
Kabul International Airport.
简称KIA，“在行动中被杀"
K.I.A.! "Killed In Action."
再次感谢各位搭乘我们的航班
<i>Once again, we thank you for flying with us.</i>
抱歉
Sorry.
Uh, sorry.
见鬼
Shit.
不，谢谢，不，谢谢
No, thank you. No, thank you.
贝克小姐？
Miss Baker?
我是法希姆
I am Fahim.
法希姆，嗨，很高兴见到你
Oh, Fahim, hi! Pleased to meet you.
车子就在这，我们走吧
The car is over here and we go.
戴上你的头巾，不要脸的婊子
Cover your head, shameless whore!
她说"欢迎来到阿富汗"
She says, uh... "Welcome to Afghanistan."
好的，我们走
Okay, let's go.
这是你在这里使用的手机 号码就在后面
Here is your local mobile. The number is on the back.
是的，我上周要了一些钱 现在还没到
Yeah, I ordered some money last week. Still in the post.
- 我下周给你答复 - 好的
- I'll fix you up next week. - Okay.
是的，这里的空气得 花点时间才能适应
Yes, the air here takes some getting used to.
有一股排泄物的味道
It's quite polluted with feces.
她来了，你好吗，金姆？
Ah, here she is! How are you, Kim?
欢迎来到斯坦，我叫尼克
Welcome to the Stan. My name's Nic.
我负责你的安全 我来给你拿包
I'll be doing your security. I'll take your bag.
法希姆，警察对我停车在这 唧唧歪歪了
Fahim. The police are giving me shit for parking here.
他们只想要钱
They just want money.
等等，不，你需要钱吗？ 因为他们给我钱了
Wait, oh, no. Um, do you need money? Because the network gave me money.
- 不，你留着 - 不不不，金姆，拜托
- No, keep that on you! - No, no, no! Kim, please!
滚开，好了，好了，嘿，嘿
Piss off, that's it! That's it! Hey! Hey!
- 很抱歉，抱歉 - 滚开
- I'm sorry. Sorry. - Piss off!
要记住我们在高海拔地区
Remember that we are at altitude here,
所以要记得喝够饮水
so drink plenty of water while you acclimatize.
你在哪学的英语？
Where did you learn English?
在医学院，我以前是医生
At medical school. I was a doctor.
听着，今晚好好休息
Listen, rest up tonight.
明天，我送你去你入驻的基地
Tomorrow, I'll drive you to the base for your embed.
只能带一个袋子
And just one bag,
要多带袜子和短裤
but make sure you pack extra socks and knickers.
我指的是"短内裤"，懂吗？
That's like, um, it's like "panties," yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
那么，你之前去部队体验过生活吗？
So, you've been embedded before, then?
也不是，我们在2001年 接受过在敌方地区生存的训练
Not really. We all did hostile-zone training in 2001.
他们教我们在被人 抓住时要记得配合
They taught us to open our mouths if we get mortared...
诸如此类的东西
That kind of stuff.
好的
Okay.
日安，卡达尔
G'day, Qadar.
（达里语）
一路上都是排泄物的气味
The feces smell all the way to here.
金姆，你的房间在楼上
Your room, Kim, is upstairs.
是的，他们很喜欢这个
Yeah, they're bloody addicted.
那个家伙就曾因为下毛片 把电脑活活下爆炸了
That one melted a laptop downloading porno.
我是贾维德
Jaweed, yes,
他喜欢看人兽片
he likes to watch men with donkeys.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
太不幸了
It's unfortunate.
金姆，这位是高布莱恩
Kim, this is Tall Brian.
我是布莱恩·霍珀，高布莱恩
Brian Hooper. Tall Brian.
- 嗨 - 我是你的摄影师
- Hi. - I'm your shooter.
那么，这附近还有一个比你矮的 名叫布莱恩的人？
So, is there another Brian around here somewhere that you're taller than?
矮布莱恩，路透社的人
Short Brian. Works for Reuters.
你们中不能有一个就叫"布莱恩"吗？
Couldn't one of you just be "Brian"?
说的对，我没想过
Fair enough. Didn't think of that.
对了，矮布莱恩死了
Also Short Brian's dead.
- 该死，真的吗？ - 是的
- Oh, fuck. Really? - Yes.
总之，欢迎来到游乐园
Anyway, welcome to the Fun House.
甜蜜之家
Home sweet home.
这是你的房间
This is your room.
有洗澡的地方吗？
Is there a shower?
一个习惯于战争的民族
<i>A nation accustomed to war</i>
再次迫切需要回归正轨
<i>once again seeks a return to normality.</i>
没有哪个地方比这里 更具有象征意义
<i>And nothing symbolizes that effort more than this place,</i>
喀布尔动物园
<i>the Kabul Zoo.</i>
不，不是吧，动物园？
No, he didn't. The zoo?
回去睡吧
Go back to Wapping.
你这该死的游客
You fucking tourist!
该死，抱歉，我想找洗澡的地儿
Uh, shit. Sorry. I'm trying to find the shower?
你是那新来的姑娘
You're the new girl.
我的天，我是金姆·贝克
Oh, my God. Uh... Kim Baker.
我刚从纽约到这里
Just got here from New York.
我是谭雅，我的天
I'm Tanya. Oh, my God,
这里多一个女人真是太好了
it's so nice to have another woman in the house!
我喜欢你的唇彩，是什么牌子的？
I love that lippy color. What is that?
不，那些是真正的裂痕
No, they're just really chapped.
可怜的家伙，我能帮你什么？
Oh, you poor thing. Can I get you anything?
抱歉，我吓坏了 因为我看过
I'm sorry, I'm freaking out because I saw your
你在克伦加尔插队的 特别报道，那太棒了
special about your embed in Korengal, and it was amazing.
谢谢你，说的真好
Thank you. That's so sweet.
- 在哪能洗澡？ - 好的，走这边
- Where's the shower? - Yes. This way.
我能请你帮个忙吗，金姆？
Can I ask a favor, Kim?
- 你不用勉强答应 - 好的，问吧
- And absolutely feel free to say no. - Yeah, sure.
我也不想提及
I hate to even bring it up.
- 我感觉这样很鲁莽 - 不，没事的
- I feel so rude even asking this. - No, it's fine.
我能上你的安保人员吗？
Can I fuck your security guys?
什么？
What? Oh.
请你自便
By all means, yeah.
是吗？我是说，我也不想这样
Yeah? I mean, I wouldn't ask,
但是因为一些原因
it's just that for some reason,
VBC采用了美国的承包商
the VBC use an American contractor
我无意冒犯，但是他们都
and, I mean, no offense, but they're all, like,
留着山羊胡，又胖又壮实
goatees and "fat-strong."
你懂吗？但是澳洲人 和新西兰人很火辣
You know? But the Aussies and Kiwis are so hot.
好的，我懂了，别客气
Right. I get it. Be my guest.
你确定？别因为讲礼貌才那么说
You sure? Don't just say that to be polite.
不，是真的，是真的
No, I wouldn't. I'm not.
包括尼克？你不把尼克 留给自己用吗？
Even Nic? You don't want Nic for yourself?
尼克？
Nic?
不，我不想，不
No. I don't. No.
那是不可能发生的 所以你不用客气
That's... No, that would never happen. So you're good.
嘿，不，金姆，别那样说 你可以上了尼克
Hey! No, Kim, don't say that. You could have Nic.
在阿富汗，你可是个大美人
In Afghanistan, you're a serious piece of ass.
谢谢，真会说话
Thank you. That's nice.
因为你是，我是说
Because you're what, I mean, you're like,
你在纽约大概能打六七分？
a seven, a six or seven in New York?
在这里，你能打九分
Here, you're a nine.
甚至是十分
Borderline ten.
这叫做"喀布尔的美"
It's called "Kabul Cute."
你在这里是不是15分？
What are you here, like a 15?
是的
Yeah.
Huh.
关键是，我在家有男友
The thing is, I have a very serious boyfriend at home,
所以，你不用客气
so, you're good.
好的，那就过两个月再来找我
All right, well, come talk to me in two months
到时候你就知道什么叫欲求不满了 洗澡去那边
when your pussy's eating your leg. Shower's that way.
你好吗？
How you doing?
这里太萧条了
It's bananas here. It's, um...
空气中一直充斥着一股屎尿味
My nose is running. There's shit in the air,
是真的
literally.
还有
And.
我想我做不到
I don't think I can do this.
做什么？
<i>Do what?</i>
金姆？
<i>Kim?</i>
我认为我做不到
I don't think I can do this.
你能看到...我不，喂
<i>Can you see... I don't... Hello?</i>
见鬼
Shit.
（帕尔旺省巴格拉姆空军基地）
抱歉，上校，作为一名记者 我是不能接受礼物的
I'm sorry, Colonel, I can't accept gifts as a journalist.
好的
Okay.
那么寄宿，交通运输
So lodging, transport,
食物和保护 就是你所能接受的东西？
chow and protection, that's all you can accept?
我将尽力保持客观
I'll do my best to stay objective.
我不在乎你是否能完成任务 我在乎的是我的手下能否完成
I don't care if you can do your job. I care if my men can.
贝克小姐，你熟悉"四十四”理论吗？
Are you familiar with the term "four-ten-four", Miss Baker?
没听说过，上校
I am not, Colonel.
指的是在祖国能打四分的女人
It refers to women who are fours back home
到了国外就能得十分
become tens when they ship out
当他们回到美国本土 就又只能打四分了
and when they're back stateside, they become fours again.
你的意思是我能打四分？
Are you saying I'm a four?
我说的是你背着 一个该死的橙色背包
I'm saying you carry an orange fucking backpack.
我看过不少人在这个 地方做了错误的决定
I've seen people with actual experience make bad decisions here.
所以当你和我的人在 外面执行任务时
So while you're outside the wire with my men,
就千万不要让他们分心，明白吗？
you will in no way distract them, understood?
你是在让我别和你的士兵们上床吗？
Are you asking me not to sleep with your soldiers?
不，不是士兵们，是海军陆战队员
No, not "soldiers." Marines.
你来这里不是为了睡遍
You're not here to sleep with
或者勾引遍我的陆战队员
or perform jobs of any type on my Marines.
明白了吗，贝克小姐？
Clear copy, Miss Baker?
- 懂了 - 很好
- Copy that. - Good.
只要我们找到合适的时机 就会把你送走的
We'll get you out to a FOB as soon as we find a ride for you.
在此期间，斯特恩上尉
In the meantime, Captain Stern here
将会尽量为你安排"一瓶湿的烈酒"
will see to it that you get a wet hootch.
什么？
A what?
是指能洗澡的帐篷
It's a tent with a shower.
除非你更愿意做不带 沐浴设施的帐篷
Unless you'd prefer a dry hootch.
我不愿意，长官
I would not, sir.
抱歉
Sorry.
你能说出你的名字和军衔吗？
Could you just... State your name and rank?
三级军士长克林顿·J·赫德
Gunnery Sergeant Clinton J. Hurd.
好的，该死的
All right. Uh... Dang it!
那么，你认为阿富汗尼人 喜欢我们在这吗？
So, do you believe the Afghani people are happy about our presence here?
不，阿富汗人才是指人
No, Afghans are the people.
阿富汗尼是货币名称
Afghanis is the currency.
没错，我知道，谢谢你
That's right. I knew that. Thank you.
你在这里是为了执行什么任务？
What do you believe your mission to be here?
女士，你的裤子上有张贴纸
Ma'am, you got a sticker on your pants.
这让我犯强迫症了，女士
It's bugging the shit out of me. Ma'am...
法希姆
Fahim.
你是因为什么入伍的？
What inspired you to enlist originally?
我是阿诺·施瓦辛格的影片 《铁血战士》的忠实粉丝
I'm a big fan of the movie <i>Predator</i> with Arnold Schwarzenegger.
我们一样高
We're the same height.
你认为伊拉克的战争 影响到了你们这里的环境吗？
Do you think the war in Iraq has affected your resources here?
抱歉，女士，我无权回答那个问题
I'm sorry, ma'am, I'm not authorized to answer that question.
我得说我们都想错了波斯
I'd say we're both on the wrong side of Persia, ma'am.
伊拉克还算是好的
Iraq is where you get some right now.
这里简直不能忍
Here just has shit all.
你们经常出去巡逻吗？
Are you guys getting outside the wire much?
是的，女士，大部分时候...
Yes, ma'am. Most days. Uh...
我们会出去帮助 社区工程的建设之类的
You know, we help out with community projects and all.
还有挖井...
And wells. Uh...
有时候晚上我们会 和武装势力发生冲突
And sometimes at night we shoot the big gun,
- 但是，这里很和平 - 天啊
- but, you know, it's quiet here. - Jesus!
我们甚至不穿防弹衣
We don't wear IBAs on the FOB.
我甚至不给武器装弹药，因为
I don't even chamber a round in my weapon anymore, because,
你懂得，我觉得走火 比塔利班还可怕
you know, I figure accidental discharge is scarier than the Taliban.
因为伊拉克的战争 你觉得人们忘了阿富汗的事了吗？
With Iraq, do you feel like people have forgotten about Afghanistan?
这个嘛...
Oh, well...
是的，夫人，我觉得这是 十分贴切的描述
Yes, ma'am. I'd say that surely is the word for it.
这里进行的是一场被遗忘的战争
This here's a forgotten war.
并不是头等重要的
It's capital F, capital W.
你的名字和军衔？
What's your, uh... Your name and rank?
我是印第安3-5连队的 一等兵考夫林
I'm Lance Corporal Coughlin, India Company 3-5.
谢谢你
Thank you.
金姆，你的头发
Kim. Your hair.
谢谢，法希姆
- Thanks, Fahim. - Mmm-hmm.
你真可靠
You really are a fixer.
月亮出来了
Moon's out.
Hmm.
很美
It's beautiful.
舔我的蛋吧
Suck my dick!
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是"真可怕"
- It means, "Oh, what a terrible event!" - Uh-huh.
贝克小姐
Miss Baker.
霍兰尼克上校明天要去诺顿
Colonel Hollanek is coming to Norton tomorrow
检查一下我们的任务进展情况
to check on some of our PRT work.
你和你的组员们可以跟随前往
And you and your crew are clear to tag along.
- 很好，谢谢 - 零六出发
- Great, thanks. - Rolls out at zero-six.
- 就是早上六点 - 我知道，是的
- That's 6:00 a.m. - I know that, yeah.
开火
Fire!
快点，我们走 整理好东西，我们得走了
Come on, let's go! Get this shit together! We gotta move!
交出你的背包
Fucking hands out of your pockets!
你觉得你这是在陆军部队吗？
You think you're in the fucking Army?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
这是什么？
What is this?
是我的物资和摄像器材
Uh, that's my supplies. Camera stuff.
你在逗我吗？
You fucking kidding me?
这是个橙色的袋子 不，夫人，不准带上我的车
This is an orange ruck. No, ma'am. Not on my vehicle.
乐斯菲斯店的售货员 说过这是军方级别的东西
The girl at the North Face store said it was, like, military grade.
那你要把它藏在哪？ 藏在日落的余晖里吗？
Well, where are you gonna hide it? Inside a fucking sunset?
连荷兰的军队都 不带橙色的装备
I mean, even the Dutch Army don't wear orange.
处理好
Fix it.
我要怎么处理？
How do I fix it?
拉波诺
Rapono!
得保持水分，女士
Got to stay hydrated, ma'am.
考夫林，我都没认出你来
Coughlin. I didn't recognize you.
那是因为我现在是勇者模式
That's 'cause I'm in warrior mode.
让我显得更高大
It makes me taller.
好好享受吧，女士
Enjoy the ride, ma'am.
我很想知道谁炸了我的水井
I'm dying to know who blew up my well.
正在调查，上校
Working on it, Colonel.
那可是很幸运的水井，下士
That was a nice fucking well, Corporal.
（达里语）
他说什么？
What'd he say?
那是什么意思？
What's that mean?
他想知道你是不是俄罗斯人
He wants to know if you are the Russians.
俄罗斯人？
- The Russians? - Mmm.
不
No!
不，先生，那是20年前的事了
No, sir. That was 20 years ago.
我们是来帮忙的
And we're here to help.
我是黑人
And I'm black.
现在俄罗斯人都变黑了
The Russians are blacks now.
如果我们把水井修好 你们就不能炸毁它
If we fix the well, you can't blow it up.
金姆，我刚才和一些年轻人谈过
Kim, I was talking to some of the younger men.
他们说塔利班晚上来过
They say the Taliban came at night.
我不在乎，我喝太多水了 我得撒尿
I don't care. No. I drank too much water and I have to pee.
别说了，别说了，我就要结婚了
Stop. Stop. I am engaged to be married.
好的，法希姆，我知道你理想中的女人
Okay, Fahim, I know you like your women to be, like,
是美丽而神秘的存在，好吗？
beautiful, mysterious IKEA bags, okay?
但我们确实要从阴道撒尿
But we urinate, Doctor. Out of our vaginas.
你认为你的尿液是从...
You think you urinate out the...
不，我知道这是不一样的
No. I know it's a separate thing!
天啊，帮帮我
God! Just please help me.
这里没有上厕所的地儿
There is nowhere for you to go.
我不能去问那些男人
I cannot ask these men about this.
而我也不能和那些女人搭话
And I'm not allowed to talk to the women.
好的，算了吧，我忍着 女人是很坚强的，对吧？
Fine. Forget it. I'll hold it. Women are tough, right?
你没事吧，女士？
Are you okay, ma'am?
天啊，该死的，伙计，这是新的
Gosh, damn it, man. This is a new one.
我本来很不爽你的都来 但今天我很乐意出来
I was cursing your name at 0-stupid-30, but I'm glad I came out today.
如果不是我 你今天就不用巡逻吗？
Would you not have gone on patrol today if I weren't here?
是的，我要回诺顿挖战壕
No, I'd be back in Norton filling HESCOs.
收到
Copy that.
还早着呢，这次肯定是大生意
We're still 5 mikes. It must be one hairy dump.
不，我才刚穿上衣服 该死的，赫德军士
No, I'm just getting my pants on. Damn it, Sergeant Hurd.
随便
Whatever.
抱歉，抱歉，抱歉
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
出发
Marine!
让个洞出来，贝克
Make a hole, Baker.
出发
Move out!
为什么停下了？
Why are we stopping?
领头的车子爆胎了
The lead vehicle bottomed out.
好的，注意警戒
Okay! Heads on a swivel!
这条路不是走过吗？
Didn't we come this way?
应该是的
We most surely did.
- 有人袭击 - 呆在车里
- Contact left! - Stay in the vehicle!
该死，热，热弹壳
Shit! Hot! Hot bullet things!
金姆，别下车，金姆
Kim, don't get out of the car! Kim!
Whoa!
给我趴到发动机后面去
Get down behind the engine block!
呆在那，呆在那
Stay there! Stay there!
金姆
Kim.
回到车上去
Get back in the car!
不，拜托，金姆
No, please, Kim!
女士，我让你呆着别动
Ma'am, I asked you to stay put!
那些混蛋想打死我们
Those assholes tried to shoot us!
老天爷
Jesus!
你肯定是在逗我
You have got to be shitting me!
你用一发导弹就为了炸一辆车
You just shot a Javelin at a fucking car!
那可是价值八万美金的东西
That's an $80,000 piece of ordnance!
你们中哪个天才能告诉我
Can any of you geniuses tell me the Kelley Blue Book value
一辆89年的丰田皮卡多少钱？
of a 1989 Toyota pickup?
贝克，不错
Oorah, Baker. Get some.
希望你都拍下来了，女士
I hope you got all that on film, ma'am.
因为那可是我们最强力的火力
'Cause that right there, that's what we do best.
心和理智
Hearts and minds.
是两个最适合打击的地方
That's the two best places to shoot somebody.
什么？
What?
我说过让你呆在车里
I told you to stay in the car.
好的，我回车上去
Okay, I'll get back in the car.
陆战队员们对于 伊拉克没什么好说的
<i>The Marines don't have much to say about Iraq.</i>
他们的理由是他们把 注意力都放在这里的工作上
<i>Their mantra is that they are focused on doing the job here.</i>
虽然如此，如我们所见的
<i>And even though, as we saw firsthand,</i>
针对联合军队的袭击结束了
<i>attacks against coalition forces are up,</i>
考夫林下士之前就告诉我 他依然不准备
<i>Corporal Coughlin told me earlier that he is still not planning</i>
在巡逻土中为武器装弹
<i>to lock and load his weapon when he is out on patrol.</i>
以上是本台记者金姆·贝克 从现场发回的报道
<i>Our own Kim Baker reporting for us live.</i>
欢迎
Welcome!
做的好，金姆，太残忍了
Wow, good job, Kim! Ruthless!
贱货，我们今晚要出去玩
Bitch, we are going out tonight! Whoo!
没事的，没事的，给你
It's okay. It's okay. Here.
没事的，会好的
It's okay. It's all right.
为什么我不知道你是谁
Why don't I know who you are?
你现在42岁了？
You're what, like, 42?
差不多
Sold.
为什么我从未听说过你？
Why have I never heard of you?
是的，我没做过多少 海外的报道
Yeah, I haven't done a lot of overseas reporting.
大部分做的是国内的报告文学
I've done mostly domestic <i>reportage.</i>
报告文学？
<i>"Reportage"?</i>
国内报告文学
Domestic <i>reportage.</i>
听着，这里的人都这样，没事的
Look, everyone in the Kabubble is full of shit. It's okay.
有一半人的口音是假装的
Half the accents are fake.
所谓的"特种部队的经历"都是假的
The whole "I'm ex-Special Forces" wankers are flat out lying.
报告文学
<i>"Reportage"?</i>
天啊，这是怎么回事？
Oh, Christ, what is this?
我不该偷听你们的谈话
I really shouldn't have my back to the door.
那是很糟糕的技术
It's bad tradecraft,
但是很值得和你们两位谈谈
but it's worth it to talk to you two ladies.
滚开
- Fuck off. - Ugh.
明白了
You got it.
香槟？
Champagne?
谢谢你
Thank you.
把这喝完
Finish this,
然后我们去阿克巴汉区见几个朋友
and then we'll go meet some friends in Wazir Akbar Khan.
现在我先警告你 不要和伊安上床
And I am warning you now, do not sleep with lain.
- 伊安是谁？ - 他是个大混蛋
- Who is lain? - He's a proper asshole.
- 可以走了吗？ - 是的
- Shall we? - Yeah.
那是出租车吗？
Is that a cab?
你的全名就是夏奇拉？
Is your full name Shakira?
我还因为那是哥伦比亚的绰号呢
'Cause I thought it was a Colombian nickname.
你为何那么想？
Why would you think that?
因为那个歌手
Because of the singer.
不，我知道，我开玩笑的 不，那是"感恩"的阿拉伯语
No, I know. I'm kidding. No, it's Arabic for "thankful."
金姆在美国是"冰美人"的意思
Kim is American for "white lady."
事实上，金姆在土耳其语里 是谁的意思
Actually, "Kim" means "who" in Turkish.
"那个冰美人是谁？"
"Who's that white lady?"
是金姆
It's Kim.
你就那样记住我的名字
That's so you can remember my name.
这位是伊安，伊安，这位是金姆
So... This is Iain. Iain, Kim.
金姆，金姆，金姆，做得好
Kim. Kim. Kim. Kim, nice work.
坐在和德克萨斯一般大的 国家唯一的两个女性身边
You sit next to the only two women in a country the size of Texas
真的能证明一个男人的帅气
that remind a man that you're really only okay looking.
她说你是个混蛋
Well, she said you were an asshole,
但那真的有点过了
but that's really above and beyond.
- 谁说的？ - 谭雅
- Who said that? - Tanya.
不不，我可不这么想
No. No. No. I don't think so.
很多女人都觉得我很有魅力
A lot of women find me very charming, Kim.
- 不，那不是生物学上的女人 - 是吗？
- No, not biological women. - Oh, really?
而是那种认为口音
Women who think that an accent
和人性是
is the same thing
一码事的女人
- as a personality, maybe. - Oh!
你真是能说
<i>Nae, haud yer wheesht.</i>
真是让人恼怒啊
<i>Go bile yer heid, ya wee bampot.</i>
我打赌你的下面 现在湿的不成样子了
I bet you're wetter than a submarine with screen doors now.
Oh!
我是从书上学的
I got that from a pickup book.
- 天啊 - 是的
- Jesus. - Oh, yeah.
Mmm.
你是怎么想的？
So what's your deal?
你被一些人爱抚着
You got chucked over by some guy
所以你想着"忘了他
so you think, "Forget him."
我要发现东方的美好
"I'm gonna go discover the wonders of the East,"
我要上一个苏格兰男人 然后写本书"
"and I'm gonna fuck a Scottish guy and write a book."
我就是苏格兰人
I'm Scottish, by the way.
干杯
Cheers.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. <i>- Salud.</i>
- 干杯 - 敬金姆
- Cheers. - To Kim!
这是你第一晚出来吗？
Is this your first night out?
是的
Yes.
是真的
It is, actually.
那个小混蛋
That little bastard!
不，金姆
Oh, no, Kim.
你该不会给他钱了吧？
You didn't give Egg Boy money, did you?
嘿，混蛋，嘿 你真是个小混蛋
Hey! Egg Boy! Hey! You're a little shitbird!
去死吧
祝你消化不良
I hope you get salmonella!
天啊
Oh!
我给了他一百块
I gave him, like, $100!
- 一百块？ - 什么？
- $100? - What?
一百块我也干
I'd give you my eggs for $100.
我们去哪？
Where are we going?
妓院，你会喜欢的
A whorehouse. You're going to love it.
看到了吗？
You see that?
这里是妓院，也是中餐馆
It's a brothel and a Chinese restaurant.
你记得那视频吗？
Do you remember this video?
大家都喜欢
Everybody was drawings.
我？不，谢谢
Me? Oh, no, thank you.
听着，一个月前 我在写关于玉米糖浆的故事
Look, a month ago, I was writing a story about corn syrup.
好吗？我不开心
Okay? I was not happy.
我认为我这辈子就那样了
I didn't think there was anything else out there for me.
只能等死
Just death.
然后这件事发生了...
Then this came along and...
我不在乎
I don't care.
你们会定期去检查身体吗？
Wenge, do you guys have regular access to healthcare?
他叫我混蛋
He called me a Fenian bastard.
为此我把他的牙打没了
I fuckin' showed him what for, kicked his teeth in, the cunt.
谭雅？她有什么故事？
Oi, Tanya? What's her story?
她有男友，她现在神志不清，好吗？
She has a boyfriend. And she's unconscious, okay?
这两个条件以前可阻止不了你
Not that either of those things have ever stopped you before.
不是的，不是的
That's not true. That's not true.
首先，我害怕男友们
- Firstly, I'm afraid of boyfriends. - Mmm-hmm.
其次，我是个绅士
Secondly, I'm a gentleman.
什么？根据某些人的记录
What? According to no less an authority than Grace Mugabe.
我是帮女士开过门的
I held a door open for her once.
让我玩玩躲猫猫
Let me just have a little peekaboo.
走开
Get out!
这样不坏
Actually, not bad.
- 我想我错过了 - 住手
- I think I missed one. - Stop!
这样挺好的，来吧
<i>Il y a du monde au balcon. Pas mal.</i>
金姆？
Kim?
你没事吧，伙计？
You all right there, mate?
你为什么要知道？
Oh, wouldn't you like to know?
嘿，我只是关心她的安危
Hey. I'm just talking about her safety.
尼克是金姆的保镖
Nic here does security for Kim, Iain.
好的，好吧
Right, well!
我走了，失陪
I'm off. Excuse me.
- 失陪 - 晚安
- Excused. - Good night.
- 再见，亲爱的 - 再见
- Bye, darling! - Good night.
最好的尼克
The best, Nic!
那是欧普拉
Oh, that's Oprah.
喂
Hello.
是我，法希姆，你准备好出发了吗？
It's Fahim. Are you ready to go?
去哪，伙计，今天周六
Go where, dude? It's Saturday.
周五是穆斯林人唯一的休息日
Friday is the only day off in the Islamic week.
我没得去采访
We have interviews.
不，那可说不通，那...不
No! That was not made clear. That's... No.
那是废话，不行
That's bullshit, Fahim. No.
金姆，今天我们要去见 阿里·马苏德·萨迪克
Kim, today we are meeting Ali Massoud Sadiq.
我做了研究，他就要成为司法部长了
<i>I sent research. He's likely to be Attorney General.</i>
- 请等等 - 请你出来
- Please hold. - Please come outside.
这和我们美国人的做法不同
This is against what I believe as an American.
抱歉，但我们必须得去
I am sorry, but we have to go.
我的鞋子，该死
<i>Oh, my shoes. Shit.</i>
你想采访我，阿赫迈德赛先生？
You wish to interview me, Mr. Ahmadzai?
是的，萨迪克先生 还得拍摄下来
I do, Mr. Sadiq. Yes, on camera.
阿赫迈德赛先生
Mr. Ahmadzai,
我只是一个
I am a person of,
一个小人物而已
of no consequence.
你很快也许就能成为
Well, you soon might be
阿富汗第二权利的人
the second most powerful person in Afghanistan.
阿赫迈德赛先生
Mr. Ahmadzai,
我负责了内政部的一个小部门
I run a small department inside the Interior Ministry.
美国人为何对我感兴趣？
What possible interest could I be to the Americans?
因为你所在的部门 对于预防暴力
Because your Ministry for the Prevention of Vice
和提倡美德的做法
and the Encouragement of Virtue
听起来和之前塔利班的手段很像
sounds a lot like the Taliban's old Ministry of Vice and Virtue.
你认为呢？
Don't you think?
金姆·贝克
- Kim Baker. - Mmm-hmm.
当塔利班掌权的时候
When the Taliban was in power,
他们有自己的伊斯兰教法
they enforced their version of sharia.
其中一条法令规定
One of their edicts was a rule that
所有的男子必须剃光阴毛
all men must shave the hair of their pubis.
他们会带着一小把 木质标尺上大街
They would walk the streets carrying a small wooden rod,
像个木钉
a dowel,
然后用它在男人的裤子上滚动
which they would roll along the front of a man's trousers.
如果某个男人的阴毛 长到影响了木钉的滚动
If a man's pubic hair was long enough to curl around the dowel,
他们就会打他
they would beat him.
现在，我问你
Now, I ask you,
我看起来像是那种
do I look like a man to walk the streets
会带着木钉上街的人吗？
carrying a hair-of-the-pubis dowel?
不，先生，你不像
No, sir, you do not.
我回到这个国家是为了拯救它
I returned to this country to save it.
我是美国的朋友
I am a friend of America.
所以你才更应该让我采访你啊
Which is why you should let me interview you,
这样大家才能明白这点
so people can understand that.
金姆，我很喜欢你
I like you, Kim.
我喜欢你叫嚣
I like your mouthiness.
- 这词没说错吧？ - 没错，没错
That is a word, yes?
这让我回想起了住在伦敦的时候
It reminds me of my time living in London.
你让我又找了年轻的感觉
You make me feel like a young man again.
但我不了解你
But I do not know you.
我们怎么才能互相了解，金姆？
How can we get to know each other, Kim?
嗯？
Hmm?
对，棒极了，金姆！
Yes, excellent, Kim!
给她戴块穆斯林头巾 她就能成为一个帅气的男孩了
Put a turban on her, she'd make a very handsome boy.
你好吗？你在那边还好吗？
<i>How are you? You okay there?</i>
那是什么声音？
<i>What the hell was that?</i>
可能这附近有人办婚礼吧
It's probably just a wedding somewhere nearby.
他们喜欢在婚礼上鸣枪庆祝
They like to shoot off guns at weddings here.
你知道的，你可是弗罗里达人
You get it, you're from Florida.
有意思
<i>Funny.</i>
我上一次见你是什么时候了？
<i>When was the last time I saw you?</i>
6月？
<i>Since June?</i>
抱歉我上个月没回去
I'm sorry that I didn't get back last month.
我周四会在纽约
I can be in New York by Thursday.
我很想你，也很想见你，而且我...
I miss you and I want to see you. And I...
我得...
I have...
又停电
Oh, not again.
我讨厌这该死的机场
I hate this fucking airport.
要我从纽约给你们带点什么吗？
Can I bring you guys anything from New York?
给我们带份6罐精选红酒就行了
Just bring us back a six pack, eh?
- 我是金姆 - 金姆·贝克？
- This is Kim. <i>- Kim Baker?</i>
我是萨迪克
It is Sadiq.
萨迪克先生，嗨
Mr. Sadiq, hi.
采访一次巴夏·汗怎么样？
How about an interview with Pacha Khan?
巴夏·汗，那个军阀？
Pacha Khan, the warlord?
巴夏·汗是个商人
<i>Pacha Khan is a businessman.</i>
你愿意吗？
Would you like that?
好，行啊，但我现在 正在去纽约，见我男朋友的路上
Uh, yeah. Yeah. But I'm on my way to New York to see my boyfriend.
你会成为从苏维埃战争之后
<i>You will be the first Western journalist</i>
采访他的第一个西方记者
<i>to interview him since the Soviet War.</i>
明天怎么样？
<i>Shall we say tomorrow?</i>
好，行，当然，谢谢
Okay, yes, of course. Thank you.
- 怎么了？ - 回车里去
- What? - Back in the car.
在这等着
Wait here.
（达里语）
没事了，来吧
It's okay, come.
（帕施图语）
她是穆斯林吗？
She is a Muslim?
对
Yes.
她有为我祷告吗？
Have her pray for me.
巴夏·汗，她是个土耳其人
She is Turkish.
反正你也听不懂她的话
You wouldn't understand her anyway.
嗯
Hmm.
- 好，可以了 - 好！
- Okay. Yes. - Yeah?
好
Okay.
巴夏·汗，谢谢您的盛情款待
Pacha Khan, thank you for your kind hospitality.
（啪施图语）
给她戴块穆斯林头巾 她就能成为一个帅气的男孩了！
Put a turban on her and she would make a handsome boy!
怎么了？
What?
没什么
No.
金姆，祝贺
Oh, Kim. Cheers.
嗨
Hi.
感觉很棒吧？
What a rush, yeah?
巴夏·汗？是啊 感觉肾上腺素飙升，大家都...
Pacha Khan, yeah. It's like, adrenaline. Everyone was...
好极了
Good job.
是啊，挺顺利的
Yeah, it went well.
但，你知道，我...我当时...
But, you know, I was... I was in the...
正坐在回家的新西兰航空的飞机上
The New Zealand SAS back home.
而今天就像跳飞机一样
And today felt like jumping out of an airplane.
或者说，你知道的，就像做爱
Or like, you know, like having sex.
金姆！
Kim!
谭雅买了威士忌 那个不会持续太久，所以...
Tanya's got scotch. It won't last long, so...
尼克，我们也欢迎你，大混球！
Nic, you're welcome, too, you big cunt!
对了，这其实是个亲昵的词
That's a term of affection, by the way.
小贱人，你这时候不是应该在纽约嘛
You were supposed to be in New York, sneaky girl.
是啊，克里斯真的超级不爽
Yeah, Chris is not super pleased.
克里斯肯定气炸了
Chris can suck a fat one.
我想看看他们有没有刊登我的故事
I'm trying to see if they put my story up,
但是网络一直连接不上！
but this Internet connection is the worst!
见鬼，贾维德！
Oh, Goddamn it, Jaweed!
天呐！
Oh, Christ!
真的吗？
- Really? - Wow.
不过，话说回来
Although, donkeys aside,
他是个很棒的中间人
- he's a good fixer. - Mmm.
不了，谢谢，还要准备早间节目
Oh, no, thanks. Morning shows.
你有他们早上想看到的东西？
You have something they want for the mornings?
也许吧，我不知道，可能吧
Maybe. I don't know. Maybe.
嗯
Hmm.
那是我想弄明白的事
That's what I'm trying to see.
你知道，我听说他已经联系上了部落
You know, I heard that he has contacts in the Tribals.
和真正的塔利班份子联系上了
Like real Taliban contacts.
- 贾维德？ - 贾维德
- Jaweed? - Jaweed.
- 不会吧 - 显然啊
- No fucking way. - Mmm, apparently.
你会干吗？你会去那吗？
Would you do that? Would you go down there?
是啊，当然，只要时机合适
Yeah, sure, if it was the right call.
是啊，但你怎么知道时机合不合适？
Yeah, but how do you know if it's the right call?
操，我也不知道
Fuck, man, I don't know.
这不就是我们为什么喝酒，嗑药
That is why we drink, do drugs
和陌生人在餐厅卫生间乱搞的原因吗？
and shag strangers in restaurant bathrooms.
（克里斯正在呼叫）
金姆，你没事吧？怎么了？
<i>Kim, are you okay? What's going on?</i>
天呐，抱歉，几点了？
Oh, shoot. Oh, sorry, what time is it?
我不知道，我现在西雅图
<i>I don't know. I'm in Seattle.</i>
老天，我还以为你在婚礼上中枪了呢
<i>God, I thought you got shot at a wedding or something.</i>
- 上帝啊，金姆！ - 没有
<i>- Jesus, Kim!</i> - No.
抱歉，长话短说吧...
Sorry. So, just real quick...
我希望你来看我
I want you to come visit me.
去阿富汗看你？真的？
<i>In Afghanistan? Really?</i>
我积攒了很多里程
I mean, I've got tons of miles.
我可以给你买头等舱的票
I could fly you first class.
我得看看日程，估计这个月没戏
<i>I have to look at a calendar. I don't think I can do it this month.</i>
我要在这待到至少15号
<i>I'm here until, like, at least the 15th.</i>
不过，等我回去后，可能...
<i>But when I get back maybe...</i>
- 克里斯，谁在你床上？ - 什么？
- Who is in your bed, Chris? <i>- What?</i>
不，那是我的包
<i>No, that's my bag.</i>
自己看镜子吧，人渣
Look in the mirror, dipshit.
老天，你这个混蛋 真不可思议，不可思议！
My God. You motherfucker. Unbelievable. Unbelievable!
你他妈的给我冷静点！
<i>You calm the fuck down!</i>
听着，你都几个月没在家了
<i>Listen, you haven't been home in months.</i>
你他妈连我的生日都忘了
<i>You forgot my fucking birthday!</i>
对，都是我的错，好极了 克里斯，你真是个天才
Oh, right, it's my fault. Great, Chris. You're a genius.
我还在帮你养那些愚蠢的植物
<i>And I kept your stupid fucking plants alive,</i>
而你却让我们之间的感情枯萎死亡
<i>but you let this relationship wither and die!</i>
这些台词都是你事先想好的吗？
Ugh! Did you have that prepared?
- 什么？ - 人渣！
<i>- What?</i> - Pussy!
知道吗？祝你在西雅图玩的愉快
You know what? Have fun in Seattle.
你应该去参观摇滚博物馆
You should go to the Rock 'n' Roll Museum.
那糟透了，正好适合你
It sucks. You'll fit right in.
你是在逗我吗？
Are you shitting me?
法希姆
Fahim.
我们再申请一次植入吧
Let's apply for another embed.
因为我想离开喀布尔
Because I want to get out of Kabul.
我就是需要离开喀布尔
I just need to get out of Kabul.
我需要“自我放松”，没错
I need "me time", exactly. That's...
瞧？我早跟你说了，奥普拉杂志
See? I told you that <i>O</i> magazine
能提升你对女人的理解
would increase your understanding of women.
嘿，你们是3-5部队的吧？
Hey, you guys are 3-5, right?
你认识考夫林下士吗？
Do you know a Corporal Coughlin?
不认识，女士
No, ma'am.
抱歉，我才来2个月
Sorry, but I've only been here for a couple months.
女士，如果你把一只脚 放在另一只脚的前面
Ma'am, if you set one foot in front of the other,
那当我们撞到简易爆炸装置时 你失去双腿的可能性会更小
there's less chance you lose both feet if we hit an IED.
各位，准备
<i>Vides, make ready.</i>
老天，如果是这种战争
Man, we are definitely losing the war
那我们输定了
when it comes to this particular well.
我对天发誓，他们又炸了一口井
I swear to God, they blow up another well,
我又弄丢了一双鞋
I take another pair of boots off.
那他妈的就像抢椅子游戏
It's like fucking musical chairs.
嘿，我要不要为你的婚礼买条礼服？
Hey, do I have to buy a dress for your wedding?
不用，在喀布尔，你穿什么都行
No. Whatever you wear in Kabul is fine.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Yeah? - Yes.
我唯一的请求是 希望你确保我的朋友们能到场
The only thing I ask is that you make sure my friend is there.
你朋友就是我啊
Aw, your friend is me.
我明白了
I get it.
（帕施图语）
- 赶紧的！ - 老天，斯特恩！
- Mount up! - Jesus, Stern!
将军，抱歉，嘿，将军，你有空吗？
General, excuse me. Hey. General, do you have a minute?
- 现在不行，贝克 - 只是...
- Not now, Baker. - It's just...
这里的井不是塔利班份子摧毁的
The Taliban haven't been destroying the well here.
而村子里的女人们正在摧毁它
The women of the village are destroying it.
他们是这么跟我说的
Or so they tell me.
我们为那些女人挖了好几次那口井
We dug that well several times for the women
这样她们就不用跋涉到河边去
so they don't have to walk to the river.
但她们想到河边去
But they want to walk to the river.
那是她们唯一能交友
It's their only chance to be social
聊天，你知道，一起聚聚的机会
and gossip and, you know, hang out.
我觉得她们有很多过去的苏维埃地雷
I think that they have a bunch of old Soviet landmines,
她们只需要埋下一颗 再在上面扔个小石子
and they just prop one up and throw rocks at it.
金姆，你是否感觉 你在为那个关卡配备人手
Kim, did you ever feel like you're manning that tollgate
然后工程师喊着： “我找到了生铁，我找到了生铁”
and the engineer's yelling, "I got pig iron, I got pig iron"?
不，我不明白这话是什么意思 但听着很有民间风味
No. I don't know what that means. But it's very folksy.
同时，那些女人显然不希望男人们
Also, the women, obviously, they don't want the men
了解这一点，所以她们希望
to know about this, so they are hoping
你这一次会拒绝修理那口井
that you would just refuse to repair the well this time.
好吧，她们走运了
Well, they're in luck.
我正是这么跟穆拉说的，所以...
That's exactly what I told the mullah, so...
干的好，贝克
Well done, Baker.
呼呀，将军
Hooyah, General.
陆战队员是说“呜啦”
Marines say "Oorah."
海军才说“呼呀”
The Navy says "Hooyah."
- 别把这俩混淆了 - 明白
- Don't mix those two up. - Got it.
祝你...祝你一路顺风
Have a good... Have a good ride.
金姆
Kim.
抱歉
Sorry.
- 你简直美呆啦！ - 你才美的不行呢！
- You look beautiful! - You look beautiful!
天呐
Oh, my God.
- 天呐 - 噢，不！
- Oh, my God. - Oh, no!
金姆！
Kim!
什么情况？
What the dick?
为什么法希姆跟我说，我可以随便穿？
Why did Fahim tell me I could dress like this?
他不希望你为此破费
Well, he didn't want you to have to go buy something.
老天，我都只洗了留海
Oh, my God. I only washed the front of my hair.
给，知道吗？
Here. You know what?
我准备送给一个这个
I'm going to let you have one of these.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在我看起来棒极了
Now I look great.
现在你准备好了
Now you're ready.
现在我准备好派对了
Now I'm ready to party.
噢，她喜欢
Oh, she likes it.
- 当然 - 哇，那个...
- Sure. - Oh, wow. Well...
那比一字眉还糟 眉毛直接插进他头发里了
It was worse than a unibrow. It went all the way into his hair.
我们之所以会在这
We all have some reason
都是出于某些原因的
for being here.
你的原因是什么？
What's your reason?
你的呢？
What is yours?
我没什么好理由，我才刚到
I don't have a good one. I'm just here.
拜托，她刚都跟你讲了 她的一字眉故事了
Come on, she just told her unibrow story.
我只是...我真的没有
I just... I don't have one.
拜托
Come on.
有天晚上下班，我去了健身房 骑健身脚踏车
I was at the gym after work one night. Stationary bike.
每天都骑那同一辆车
Okay? The same bike every day.
然后我注意到
And I notice this
地毯上的压痕
indentation in the carpet,
大概在我脚踏车前方一英尺
it's, like, a foot in front of my bike.
然后我发现那是我脚踏车原来的位置
And I realize that it's from where my bike used to be.
我已经在这辆车上骑了几千公里了
I have done thousands of miles on this bike
结果我却在倒退
and I have gone backwards.
毫不夸张的，我是在倒退
I have literally gone backwards.
我就是...
I just
想摆脱一切，我只想辞掉我的工作
wanted to blow everything up. I just wanted out of my job,
为百姓们写点可读的新闻
writing news scripts for dumb pretty people to read.
我希望...
I wanted...
不再去决定我是否应该
out of having to decide whether
嫁给我那个轻度抑郁症男友
I should just marry my mildly depressive boyfriend.
就这样
And that's it.
我...我无法再直视
I just... I couldn't look at that
那块该死的地毯了
fucking carpet anymore.
噢...
Oh...
好吧，事实上，这是我
Well, that is officially the most
听过的最美国白人女性的故事
American white lady story I've ever heard.
- 得了吧 - 是真的
- Shut up. - It is.
知道吗？去他妈的
You know what? Fuck that.
你是一个国外前线驻地记者
You are a battle-tested foreign correspondent.
你是一个顽强的喀布尔9.5
You're a solid Kabul 9.5.
而且你他妈还单身，对吗？
And you are fucking single, all right?
所以，健身房的那个女人 她已经死了
So that lady back at the gym, she's dead.
这才是你的人生
This is your life.
（喀布尔选举仍在继续） 除了塔利班的威胁，选举观察员们
<i>Despite Taliban threats, election observers</i>
正在报道高投票人数
<i>are reporting high voter turnout,</i>
尤其在各大城市中
<i>especially in cities.</i>
（纽约广播中心，阿富汗帕尔旺） 上周，一架英国战斗轰炸机
<i>A British fighter-bomber last week</i>
将这一化合物化为了粉末
<i>reduced this compound to rubble.</i>
（追击炮袭击了被恐怖统治的村民们） ...不合作，老天，那是一只...
<i>not to cooperate. Oh, God. Christ, there's a...</i>
残骸！这里有块残骸！
Bahzo! <i>There's a</i> bahzo <i>here!</i>
（拉姆斯菲尔德意外到访） 国防秘书长拉姆斯菲尔德意外到访
<i>The surprise visit from Secretary of Defense Donald Rumsfeld.</i>
（喀布尔的第一名女司机） 今天，喀布尔为首位女司机颁发了驾照
<i>Today, Kabul's first licensed female driver,</i>
古尔巴哈·尤瑟夫上路了
<i>Gulbahar Yousofy, hits the road.</i>
糟透了，这对女人来说糟透了
<i>That sucks. That sucks for women.</i>
谢谢
Thank you.
祝贺你晋升了
Congratulations on your promotion,
- 司法部长先生 - 谢谢
- Mr. Attorney General. - Thank you.
我之前也说过，我们本可以 在电话里完成这次谈话
As I said, we could have done this over the phone.
我只是想找一份关于坎大哈的 伊斯兰教法的声明
I'm just looking for a statement on sharia in Kandahar.
我得知，你已经和你特别的朋友
I understand that you are no longer
克里斯分开了
with your special friend Chris.
谁告诉你的？
Who told you that?
在阿富汗发生的事
Very little happens in Afghanistan
很少有我阿里·马苏德·萨迪克不知道的
that Ali Massoud Sadiq does not know about.
很少
Very little.
我能给你看点东西吗？
May I show you something?
当然
Of course.
你的办公室里有张床
You have a bed in your office.
是的
Yes.
这里有张床
There is a bed here now.
那么，对于坎大哈的伊斯兰教法 不做评论还是...
So, no comment on sharia in Kandahar or...
无可奉告
No comment.
- 我们待会儿要去维和部队吗？ - 我不知道
- We are going to ISAF later, yes? - I don't know.
记者和爆炸的梗，谁在乎呢？
Pressers and "right of boom" crap. Who cares?
我们需要来点冒险，好吗？
We need to enterprise something. Okay?
我们需要走出泡沫
We need to get out of the bubble.
球撞网了
Oh, that hit the net.
- 什么？ - 球撞网了
- The what? - It hit the net.
- 隐形的网？ - 是的
- The invisible net? - Yes.
- 我得分 - 得了吧，胡说
- My point. - Let's go. Bullshit.
金姆，你知道，你那个乡村水井的故事 之所以有吸引力
You know, Kim, the reason that your village well story got traction is
不是因为它很轰动 而是因为它关乎女性权益
because it wasn't a bang-bang, it was about women's rights.
那是篇很棒的文章
It was a brilliant piece, that.
见鬼
Oh, fucking hell.
我们应该去坎大哈
We should go to Kandahar.
不，太危险了
No, too dangerous.
不行，听说那里最近发生了液体泄漏
No way. It's a wee bit fluid down there these days,
安全起见
security-wise.
对，对你来说可能太冒险了 对吧，尼克？
Yeah, it might be a bit much for you, eh, Nic?
你这想法有点迟了
You're a bit late to the whole.
坎大哈现在已经成了屎坑了 知道吗？
"Kandahar's gone to shit" party. You know?
那等伊斯兰教法恢复 那女人们怎么办？
What about the woman thing where the sharia law is back?
而且那天，那里还发生了燃烧弹爆炸
And there was a firebombing there the other day.
对，我觉得这值得冒险
Yeah, I think it's worth the risk.
伊安，伙计，你说的轻巧
Iain, that's easy for you to say, mate,
穿着你的泳衣躺在那 给该死的花园拍照片
sitting there in your cozzie taking photos of the fucking garden.
听着，尼克，我知道你受过专门训练
Look, Nicky, I know you've been specially trained
用于保护新西兰的什么来着 见鬼的海豚？
to protect New Zealand from, what, fucking dolphins?
但我其实不是没去过战区的 知道吗？
But I'm not exactly a war zone virgin, you know?
我曾在AIG还叫AIG的时候 被他们绑架过
I was kidnapped by the AIG when they were still called that.
为什么是海豚？
Why dolphins?
海豚和新西兰有什么关系
What do dolphins got to do with New Zealand?
没关系，我只是...
Nothing to do with it. I'm just...
白色指针和鲨鱼
White pointers and sharks,
但海豚从没伤害过任何人
but the dolphins never hurt anyone.
伙计，我知道它们不伤人 我只是想说明...
I know they've not hurt anyone, mate. I'm just making the point...
我不会通过保护一种
I'm not gonna protect my country
从不伤人的动物来保护祖国
from an animal that hasn't hurt anyone.
老天
Oh, Jesus Christ.
海豚？开玩笑
Dolphins? What a joke.
如果车里还坐的下，我可以跟你去
I'll come with you in the car if there's room.
那太好了，我们要去坎大哈了
Oh, great, we're all going to Kandahar!
我先打几个电话 咱们可以开我的车去
I can make some calls. We can take my car.
金姆，如果我们要去坎大哈
Kim, if we are going to Kandahar,
你会需要买些新衣服
you will need to buy some new clothes.
不行...
I can't...
漂亮极了，我甚至都不想选举了
Ah! It's so pretty, I don't even want to vote.
我现在其实在里面朝你做鬼脸
I'm flipping you the bird in here right now.
- 法希姆，这是你的车吗？ - 是啊
- Is this your car, Fahim? - Yes.
这简直就是一堆破烂啊
This is a fucking piece of shit.
我觉得挺好的啊
I think it's very nice.
没人在盯着我看，好奇怪
No one is staring at me. It's weird.
你现在处于蓝色的监牢内
You are in the Blue Prison now.
法希姆，这些涂鸦写的是什么？
Fahim, what does the graffiti say?
“女人不许受教育”
"No education for woman."
br伊安
- Brian. - Huh?
法希姆，那边发生了什么？
Fahim, what's going on up there?
塔利班以前经常这样
The Taliban used to do this.
处决收音机和电视
Execute the radios and televisions.
（达里语）
见鬼！
Oh, shit!
（达里语）
让开！
Get out of the way!
让让，让让！
Move on! Move on!
你们不能出去，我可以
You guys can't go out there, but I can.
（达里语）
- 金姆，回来 - 金姆，等等，回来
- Kim, come back. - Kim, wait! Come back.
（达里语）
金姆，快，我们必须快点 我们必须快点
Kim, now. We must hurry. We must hurry.
上车！
Get in the car!
快离开这！
Get out of here!
那是男人的场地，金姆 只有男人能去！
That was a men's park, Kim! Men only!
操！
Fuck!
贝卡希德，法希姆
<i>Bebakhshid,</i> Fahim.
联合战斗力
coalition capacity,
优先权和支持
priorities and support.
我们现在来看看排行前12的 通行货比
Let's look now at the 12 first-tier drivers in the current COIN paradigm.
该死
Shit.
战术和制度性
Tactical and institutional...
总是难以执行
is always in purple,
没有像这样...
and noting as such...
金姆·贝克
Kim Baker.
先生，你现在有空吗？
Sir, do you have a minute?
如果我能听懂简要内容
If I'm understanding this briefing,
那我有的是时间
I have all the fucking time in the world.
好吧，我今天去了坎大哈
Okay. Well, I'm covering the girls' school
被燃烧弹烧毁的女校
in Kandahar that was firebombed
我在想，你是否能为我提供些参考
and I'm wondering if you could give me something, on background,
就关于这里的安全形势
just about the security situation here
和总体的战况
and the state of the war in general.
对，我可以给你些参考
Yeah, I can give you something.
这场战场就像一只大猩猩
This war is like fucking a gorilla.
除非大猩猩想停 否则你就要一直打下去
You keep going till the gorilla wants to stop.
我觉得我能听懂这句的意思
I think I can paraphrase that.
赶紧离开那
<i>Knock yourself out.</i>
你知道，阿富汗生产的鸦片类麻醉剂 占全世界比重的90%
You know, Afghanistan produces 90% of the world's narcotic opiates.
他们也是这么说的
- So they say. - Mmm.
我在医院工作的时候
When I worked in the hospital,
这些男人，海洛因依赖者
these men, heroin addicts,
会带一个孩子来
would come in with a child.
他们说，“噢，我儿子摔断了胳膊”
They'd say, "Oh, my son, he broke his arm."
在我们照顾孩子的时候
And while we were tending to the child,
那些男人就会偷我们的吗啡
the men would steal our morphine.
然后我们会开始猜测 这胳膊是怎么断的
And we would wonder how the arm got broken to begin with.
法希姆，你想说的是什么？
What are we talking about, Fahim?
嗯
Hmm.
人体会产生自身的海洛因
The human body produces its own heroin.
事实上，争斗或逃避的直觉
In fact, when the fight-or-flight instinct
是作用于下丘脑的
is activated in the hypothalamus,
你的身体会释放内啡肽 多巴胺和降肾上腺素
your body releases endorphins, dopamine and norepinephrine.
那就好比是同时摄入海洛因，可卡因 和安非他明
That is heroin, cocaine and amphetamine, all at once.
好吧，我们这段阿富汗式的对话
Okay, great. Are we having the Afghan version of this conversation,
如果在纽约，是否就能
where in New York we would have
在5分钟前，就已经明白意思了？
gotten to the point, like, five minutes ago?
我们有理由相信一个人
There is a reason to believe that a person
会沉迷于这种兴奋
can get addicted to this type of high.
士兵，运动员...
Soldiers, athletes...
战地记者，明白
War reporters. Got it.
一种瘾对剂量的需要总是会越来越大
An addict always needs a greater and greater dosage.
然后人们就会犯错，会受伤
And then people make mistakes, people get hurt.
我明白了，你刚结婚，我也许
I get it. You're a newlywed. I can
可以让他们每天得到125美金
probably get them to go up to $125 a day.
咱们还是
Let us have the
用美国的方式来谈话吧
American version of this conversation.
好吧
Okay.
我已经不想再和你合作了
I do not want to work with you anymore.
不，好，等等，法希姆 我知道我搞砸了
No, okay, wait. Fahim, I know I fucked up.
我觉得你不知道
I do not think you do.
- 听我说 - 金姆，不
- Hear me out. - Kim, no.
我刚结婚，我想生孩子
I am now married. I want to have children.
那种事不会再发生了，不会了...
It will not happen again. It's not gonna...
我以为自己在追一头鹿 结果发现自己正在被一只鬣狗追
"I ride after a deer and find myself chased by a hog."
“我计划了我想要的
"I plot to get what I want"
结果却进了监狱
"and I end up in prison."
我挖陷阱想诱捕他人 结果自己却落入其中
"I dig pits to trap others and I fall in."
我应该怀疑我想要的是否正确”
"I should be suspicious of what I want."
我不明白这话的意思
I don't know what that means.
你明白
You do.
法希姆？
Fahim?
我在这有些呼吸不过来了
I can't breathe in here.
该去散个步了
Time to take a walk.
我得到外面去
I have to go outside.
我得回家
I have to go home.
（达里语）
戴上你的头巾
Put on your headscarf.
该死
Shit.
走错门了
It's the wrong house.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
金姆？
Kim?
你在干嘛呢？
What the hell are you doing?
给
Here.
金姆，喝点水，好吗？你没事吧？
Kim, sip that. Okay? You all right?
继续喝，没事的，都没事了
Keep sipping that. You're all right. It's okay.
没事了，嘿
It's okay. Hey.
嘿，都没事了
Hey, it's all right.
喂，有点意思啊
Oi. Now, that there was a bit of fun.
- 你有病啊？ - 好吧，伙计...
- Are you mental? - Okay, mate...
我不是你的伙计，我再问你一遍
I'm not your mate. I'm gonna ask you again,
你他妈的有病吗？
are you fucking mental?
- 算了，伊安，那不是他的错 - 你的职责是什么？
- Come on, lain, it's not his fault. - What's your job again? Hmm?
因为如果我因为 从一个日本旅行作家那
Because if I hadn't come back to see you lot
偷了一瓶清酒
because I stole a bottle of sake
而没有回来找你...
from a Japanese travel writer...
等等，你有清酒？
Wait, you have sake?
你可能会害死她，伙计！
you could've killed her, "mate!"
滚开
Oh, fuck off.
老天！妈的！
Jesus! What the fuck?
伙计，你他妈的干什么？
Dude, what the fuck?
你他妈的刚是揍了我吗？
Did you fucking sucker punch me?
你弄断了我的鼻子
You broke my nose.
- 你他妈的是美国人吗？ - 你是美国佬吗？
- You fucking American? - Are you a Yank?
我是加拿大人，混蛋
- I'm Canadian, you asshole. - Ugh.
我差点和一个加拿大人上床了？
I almost fucked a Canadian?
我要是你，就躺着不动，孬种
I'd stay down if I were you, ya wee cunt.
这不是什么亲昵的词
And that's not a term of affection.
妈的
Fuck that.
天呐！
Oh, God! Mmm.
噢！
Ow!
- 等等 - 操
- Wait. - Oh, fuck.
伊安，别抱着我走啊，我又不是婴儿
Iain, don't carry me around. I'm not a fucking baby.
见鬼
- Ah! - Goddamn it.
你在干什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
- 脱掉 - 我在努力脱掉！
- Take it off. - I'm fucking trying to take it off!
老天，我要用力地干你
Oh, God, I'm gonna put it in you so fucking hard,
- 一定让你爽翻天 - 嘘，别出声
- you're gonna fucking get it. - Shh. Don't talk.
我想要你嘴里的一切
I want everything in your mouth.
伊安，闭嘴
Iain, just shut it.
我带你躺下，来
I'll take you lying down, come on.
你有那种奇小的阴茎吗？
Do you have one of those weird little penises?
不！我喜欢这种姿势
No! This is how I want to go.
不，我不想看见自己
No, I don't want to see myself.
走开！
Roll off!
好吧，舔它
Okay, fuck it.
老天，我真他妈的...
Oh, God, I fucking...
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我只是把手指放进你的嘴里
I'm just putting my fucking finger in your mouth.
嘘，不！
Shh. No!
来吧，用你的嘴吞下全部
Come on, just put everything in your mouth.
你想走了吗？
Do you want me to go?
不
No.
你下面的毛毛很蓬松
There's aught like a good shag.
好吧，我们都成熟点
Okay, let's try to be adults here.
我觉得我们很成熟啊
I think we were.
显然，这只是一时冲动，对吗？
Obviously this was just a Kabubble thing, right?
当我们
Just a
其中一人高潮时，那只是个有趣的错误
fun mistake where one of us had an orgasm.
我是说，我们俩当时都很火大 然后你就
I mean, we're both in a really bad place. And then you
揍了尼克
punched Nic.
我不知道，是内啡肽在作祟，对吗？
I don't know. It's endorphins, right?
不，不是
Nope, that's not what this is.
不，你不用献殷勤
No, you don't need to be gallant.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我很喜欢你，金姆·贝克
I fancy you, Kim Baker.
真的
I do.
这个国家有那么多的女人 我偏偏选了你
Of all the dozens of women in this country, I chose you.
不，你没有，因为这不是我
No, you didn't, because this is not me.
是我绝对不会干出这种事
I would never do this.
确切地说，正因为你已经不再是你了
Precisely. Because you're not you anymore.
你是一时冲动，你自己也说了
You're in the Kabubble. You said so yourself.
别躲起来
Don't fucking hide.
金姆，你听说过温水煮青蛙吗？
Kim, you know the frog in the pot of water?
你一点一点地升高温度
You raise the temperature bit by bit,
而青蛙并没有意识到这点
the frog doesn't notice?
那就是这个地方
That's what this place
和这份工作对我们的所作所为
and that's what this job does to all of us.
它改变了你以前对正常的知觉
It changes your perception of what's normal until...
直到我们变成这样
until here we are.
你知道青蛙最终
You know the frog boils to death
- 被煮死了，对吧？ - 不
- at the end of that, right? - Nope.
- 是 - 不
- Yeah. - Nope.
那是我的牙刷吗？
Is that my toothbrush?
Ugh!
艾德，我坎大哈的那篇报道 是怎么回事？
<i>What's going on with my Kandahar piece, Ed?</i>
杰瑞封杀了它
<i>Jerry killed it.</i>
等等，谁？
Wait, who killed it?
杰瑞·陶布，网络总监啊，金姆
<i>Jerry Taub, head of the network, Kim.</i>
- 安吉拉人呢？ - 她走了
- What happened to Angela? <i>- She left.</i>
她现在正在为女性还是什么的 运营一个网站
<i>She's running a website for women or something.</i>
听着，在周一的会议上 我没办法打阿富汗的牌
<i>Look, I can't sell Afghanistan in Monday meetings.</i>
你的战地报道变得有些冗长 而且每天都一样
<i>Your war's got chronic same-shit-different-day-itis.</i>
好极了，艾德，那我还在这干什么？
Great. What am I even doing here, Ed?
金姆，这个我就不问了
<i>I wouldn't ask that too loudly, Kim.</i>
我想你应该会很高兴 能回到你昔日的办公桌边吧
<i>Though I'd be thrilled to have you back at your old desk.</i>
我说完了
That's all I got.
嘿，我听说尼克不干了 你还和伊安上了床！
Hey, I heard that Nic quit and you fucked Iain!
等等
Whoa, hold on.
听着，伊安的事不要再提了，好吗？
Listen, the Iain thing is not a thing, okay?
我们手的大小相同，我不能
We have the same size hands. I can't.
只是工作让你有些崩溃
It's just work has been a little frustrating.
我能理解
Yeah. I get it.
因为阿富汗的新闻已经不叫座了
Because Afghanistan doesn't rate anymore.
胡扯
That is bullshit.
宝贝，你在这找到了自己的幸运
You've got to find your own luck here, babe,
你知道的
you know that.
怎么了？
What?
怎么？那是什么？
What? What is that?
嘿！你正在部落和谭雅联系？
Hey! You're hooking up Tanya in the Tribals?
贾维德，你搞什么？
What the fuck, Jaweed?
她的网站会付给我三倍的薪水
Her network will pay me triple.
我教过你怎么清楚网络浏览记录吧？
I taught you how to clear your Internet history, okay?
范德普尔以前对你做过什么？
What has Vanderpoel ever done for you?
伙计，给我消停会儿吧
Give me a break, man.
我不管，你欠我的，你还有什么？
Whatever. You owe me. What else do you have?
你是吉尔扎伊人，对吗？ （阿富汗帕坦人的一支）
You're Ghilzai, right?
你和吉尔扎伊家族的其他成员
Do you have any other connections
有什么联系吗？
to members of the Ghilzai family?
- 你是说希克马蒂亚尔吗？ - 也许
- You mean Hekmatyar? - Maybe.
金姆，你疯了吗？拜托
Are you fucking crazy, Kim? Please.
嘿！纳比奥，嘿
Hey! Nabil! Hey.
你跟ISI的，说他知道
Are you still in touch with that ISI guy
谁杀了阿卜杜尔·哈克的那个人有联系吗？
who says he knows who killed Abdul Haq?
那个人？他两年前就死了
That guy? He's dead two years.
嘿
Hey.
噢，天啊
Oh, for fuck's sake.
麦克凯尔皮夫人
Mrs. MacKelpie.
两次？
Twice?
其实是两次半
Two and a half, actually.
噢
Ugh!
我不记得昨晚发生什么了
I don't remember what happened last night.
跟喀布尔那次一样 我被温水煮青蛙了
Kabul happened, my wee froggy in the pot.
我戴头巾了吗？我的手机在哪？
Did I not wear a headscarf? Where's my phone?
我应该扔进壁橱里了
I believe I threw your mobile in my cupboard.
为什么？
Why?
因为半途中你想打电话给谭雅
Because mid-coitus you tried to call Tanya
说什么部落里的追鹅比赛
about some bloody wild goose chase in the Tribals.
我跟你说过那个？
I told you about that?
嗯，你让我把内裤塞你嘴里后
Mmm. Well, it was hard to understand you
我基本听不清楚你想说什么
once you asked me to stuff your knickers in your mouth.
开玩笑的，金姆，没有那回事
I'm joking, Kim. That didn't happen.
见鬼，我...
Fuck. I am...
我要输了
I am fucking losing it.
我需要个胜利
I need a win.
天啊，要是你那么坚持
Christ, if you're that hard up,
我可以把我在巴达克山的故事分享给你
I'll share my Badakhshan thing with you.
什么巴达克山的故事
What Badakhshan thing?
你知道中国赢得了在那里 挖金矿的合同
You know China won the contract to mine for gold up there.
他们建造公路，机场，房屋所有那一切
They built roads, airport, housing, all that.
猜猜保护红色中国
Well, guess whose responsibility it is
在那动荡地区财产的责任
to protect the investment of Red China
在谁身上？
in this restive nation?
美国士兵，中国黄金，噢，伊安 这故事太棒了
American troops, Chinese gold. Oh, Iain, that's really good.
人们会气死的
People are gonna get mad.
我就等上面开绿灯了
Just waiting for my guy to give me the green light.
你付路费，我就把故事分享给你，简单
You pay for the trip, I'll share the story with you. Easy peasy.
真的？谢谢，那太...
Really? Thank you. That's...
我欠你一次
I owe you one.
剩下那半次呢？
Well, how about a half of one?
我们可以补上算3次
And then we can make it an even three.
好吧，或者我能请你吃早饭
Yeah. Or I could buy you breakfast.
或者补上半次，我们就算3次扯平了
Or a half of one and we can make it an even three.
我觉得早餐在金钱上有同样的价值
I think breakfast is of equal monetary value.
我的中名是欧汉
My middle name is Eoghan.
是苏格兰语，闭嘴的意思
Which is Erse... Shut up.
“让欧文闭嘴”
It's Erse for Owen.
- 欧希？ - 嗯哼
- "Oo-hee"? - Mmm-hmm.
- 伊安·欧希？ - 算了
- Iain "Oo-hee." - Don't bother.
本拉登在哪？
Where is Bin Laden?
人们以为他在巴基斯坦，对吧
People think he's in Pakistan, right?
对
Yeah.
你胡子上有鸡蛋，等等
You've got egg in your beard. Hang on.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的国兽是独角兽？
Your national animal is the unicorn.
我觉得这挺浪漫
I think it's romantic.
那是我8岁时统治的
That is the national animal of the kingdom I ruled
王国的国兽
when I was eight.
三个臭皮匠你最喜欢谁
Who's your favorite Three Stooge?
拉里，因为他的风格我最认同
Um, Larry. Because he's put upon in a way that I identify with.
他是个艺术狂对吧
He's the Art Garfunkel, right?
对
Yeah.
所以我觉得我想跟你再一起呆一会
So, I thought I might like to hang out with you for a bit.
好啊，好
Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
你真的想知道我想做什么吗
Do you really want to know what I want to do?
想啊
Yeah. Okay.
我想亲你
I'd like to kiss you.
谁猜得到呢
Who knew?
这是我的小伙计
Here's my little man.
不，伊安，这是骗局
No, Iain, don't. It's a scam.
你这么想吗？真的？
Do you think so? Really?
我知道这是不是骗局，金姆 可那又怎么样？
I know it's a scam, Kim. So what?
他还是在街上乞讨 嘿，亚伯拉罕
He's still begging in the street. Hey, Abrahaim.
好孩子
There's my boy.
我就知道能赢得你的心
I knew I'd win you over.
天啊
Jesus!
怎么回事，贾维德？他们来不来？
What the fuck, Jaweed? Are they coming or not?
来了
Here they are.
他们来了
<i>There they are.</i>
4-6800，北方6号线
4-6800, line six north.
等待许可
Standing by approval.
可以攻击目标
We are clear to engage target.
收到，可以攻击目标
Roger. Clear to engage target.
是他，我的人
It is him. That's my guy.
要是我们要去什么地方 必须开自己的车
If we go anywhere, Jaweed, we take our vehicle.
决不共用车子
No carpooling.
好
All right. Okay.
见鬼
Shit! Shit!
冷静
Stay calm.
命中
Splash.
减弱激光
Cease laser. Safe laser.
激光关闭，激光安全
Laser off. Laser safe.
我在找个人，不好意思
I'm looking for someone. Excuse me.
- 天啊，谭雅 - 嗨
- Oh, my God. Tanya. - Hi.
天啊
- Jesus. - Oy.
贾维德死了
Jaweed's dead.
安迪在手术室
Andy's in surgery.
我知道，伊安跟科林谈过了
I know. Iain talked to Colin.
天啊
Jesus!
我知道，这很操蛋
I know. It's fucked.
你知道，科林在拍
You know, Colin was rolling.
那种拍摄？你有带子？
What, like, rolling-rolling? You have tape?
整件事他都拍到了
He got the whole fucking thing.
他们一让我离开这我就要播出去
I'm going to go live with it as soon as they let me out of here.
你能相信吗
Can you fucking believe it?
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
Aye.
- 你好吗 - 你还好吗
- How are you? - You doing all right?
见鬼
Holy shit!
苏珊娜，实际上在我们看的时候
<i>And as we watch it again there, Susanna,</i>
你能看到地狱火导弹爆炸之前的瞬间
<i>you can actually see the Hellfire missile right before it detonates.</i>
巴达克山怎么了？
What is going on with Badakhshan?
啊，那雪简直要命
Ah, snow's killing us.
除非你的台历
So unless your network wants
想拿出坐直升机的钱
to stump up the money for the helicopter,
不然你就得等道路开放
we'll have to wait till they clear the passes.
金姆，外面有点情况
Kim, we have a bit of a situation outside.
噢
Oh.
什么
What?
我只是需要你看个东西
I just need you to see something.
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to interrupt.
他说他要什么了吗
Did he say what he wanted?
我不知道
I don't know.
操
Fuck.
卡达尔，卡达尔，没事，你能进去
Qadar. Qadar, it's okay. You can go in.
他只是想跟我谈谈
He just wants to talk to me.
- 好了，好了 - 没事
- Okay. Okay. - It's okay.
求你了，看在我的份上别遮住头发
Oh, please, do not cover your hair on my account.
这么美丽的头发
It's such beautiful hair.
简直就像骏马的鬃毛
It's like the hide of a fine horse.
萨迪克，你在这干什么
Sadiq, what are you doing here?
我刚关了一家妓院，正在回家路上
I was just going home from closing a woman brothel
我跟我的司机说
when I told my driver,
马勃布拉，这是我最好的朋友 金伯利住的地方
"Mahboobullah, this is where my best friend Kimberly lives!"
但她最近一直是坏朋友
But she has been a bad friend lately.
她不来电话
She does not call.
不邀请我参加她的派对
She does not invite me to her party.
对不起
I'm sorry,
但我觉得阿富汗伊斯兰共和国的
but I didn't think the Attorney General
司法部长应该不会去客人家
of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan
参加派对吧
went to parties at guesthouses.
为什么不会？
And why not?
我还是个人，不是吗
I am still a man, no?
我爱音乐
I love music.
我爱跳舞
I love to dance!
但是
But
虽然你是坏朋友
even though you have been a bad friend,
我还是想要你快乐
I want you to be happy.
你有特别的朋友吗
Do you have a special friend?
因为
Because.
我很想当你特别的朋友
I would love to be your special friend.
你愿意吗，金姆？
Would you like that, Kim?
你是坏朋友
You're a bad friend.
你是个坏朋友
You are a bad friend.
要在美国，我会把这些都写成书
In America, I would get a book deal out of this shit!
你不能这样，好吗
You can't just do this, okay?
我已经几个月没播出节目了
I haven't been on the air in months!
我最好的朋友差点死掉 我还在嫉妒她
My best friend here almost died, and I am jealous of her!
我就是...
And I am just...
都去死吧，全都去死
Fuck this! All of it!
那是个炸弹
That was a bomb.
你好，等等
Hello! So, wait!
谁在演出最前面？
Who is fronting the show?
塔克？我不知道那是谁
Tucker? No, I don't know who that is.
好，我可以通宵直播，但这...
Okay, well, I could go live for the overnights, but this is...
“卫星时间”？ 不，我有准确消息
"Satellite time?" No, I have a dedicated feed.
什么时候开始？
Since when?
我是塔克·王
<i>This is Tucker Wang.</i>
我是金姆·贝克
This is Kim Baker.
我为什么听说我没有卫星转播
Why am I being told that I don't have a sat hookup?
因为你现在加入计时工资制了
<i>Because you're on the hourly plan now.</i>
反正这节目今晚要播
<i>And either way, the show is full tonight.</i>
不，你的上级是谁
No. Who is your boss?
我要跟这个杰瑞什么陶布聊聊
I want to talk to this Jerry whatever, Taub.
好吧，听我说，杰瑞跟我 提到过一次阿富汗
<i>Okay, look, Jerry has mentioned Afghanistan to me once,</i>
还提到过知道为什么一年之内
<i>and mentioned it to know why the only good story to come</i>
报道出来的好故事 都是另一个台的
<i>out of there in a year was on another network.</i>
什么？谭雅那些？ 不，我有那样的故事
What, Tanya's thing? No, I've got shit like that.
我在等冰雪融化
I'm waiting for the snow to melt!
我要跟杰瑞谈谈
I want to talk to Jerry.
如果你能给我一个
<i>If I could just get you to get me a story</i>
别人关心的故事
<i>that somebody would care about,</i>
那就可以了，同时...
<i>it would be fine. But meanwhile...</i>
好吧，我直接去纽约
Okay, what if I come to New York
冲进杰瑞的办公室呢？ 那怎么样？
and I burst into Jerry's office? How about that?
那样会显得我没干好我的工作
<i>Well, that might look like I hadn't done my job.</i>
完美，星期三见
Perfect. See you Wednesday.
混蛋
Cunt.
金姆
Kim.
金姆，看看这些狗
Kim, look at these dogs.
这要怎么收场？
How does this end?
估计一桶冷水吧
A bucket of cold water, I suppose.
不
No.
呃
Um...
这个要怎么
How does this
结束
end?
我真的不知道，金姆
Uh, I don't really know, Kim.
我们一起变老？在乡下买幢小屋？
We grow old together? Get a cottage in the country?
养鸡？
Raise chickens?
互相喂炒蛋吃？
Eat scrambled eggs off each other?
我们挺好的，不是吗 我们总有喀布尔
Look, we're good, aren't we? We'll always have Kabul.
不，没有，我们不是“总有”
No, we won't. We won't "always have" it
因为我要回家了
because I have to go home.
不，这是家
No, this is home.
我要去纽约调整我的生活
I have to go to New York City and justify my life
为了一个叫杰瑞的家伙
to somebody named Jerry
在他夺走一切之前，然后我...
before he takes it all away, and I
我不能回去坐在办公桌后面，我不能
cannot go back to sitting at a goddamn desk. I can't.
听我说
Aye. Listen...
没人能从你身边夺走什么
No one can take it away from you.
什么都不行
Not all of it.
不管发生什么，你有我
Whatever happens, you'll have me.
这种话听着舒服，但是...
That's a very nice thing to say, but...
但是什么？
But what?
卷入两辆卡车相撞的致命事件
<i>Following a fatal traffic accident involving a coalition truck,</i>
并经历了长期压抑沮丧之后
<i>long simmering frustration</i>
今天情绪终于爆发成暴力和绝望
<i>today boiled over into violence and despair.</i>
他们杀死我们
<i>They kill us!</i>
他们杀死我们，伤我们的心
<i>They kill us and they break our hearts!</i>
我也要把这些话送给 哈米德·卡尔扎伊总统
<i>And I also give this message to President Hamid Karzai.</i>
这里到底出了什么事
<i>What the hell is happening here?</i>
我不在乎那里面是谁，我是金姆·贝克
Okay, I don't care who the hell's in there. I'm Kim Baker.
进去吧，金姆，杰瑞在等你
Go on in, Kim. Jerry's expecting you.
真是让人不爽
Well, that's fucking unsatisfying.
能替你拿包吗
Can I take your bag?
好，谢谢
Yes. Please.
你需要喝点水吗
Would you care for some water?
要
Yes.
我应该谷歌一下你的
I should've Googled you.
我一直...一直在用各种 错误的骂人语言
I've been... I've been using all the wrong swear words.
希望没有毁掉你的重要时刻
Well, I hope I didn't ruin your big moment.
听我说，盖里，我不知道 塔克跟你说了什么
Look, Geri, I don't know what Tucker has been telling you.
他说你对自己的播出时间不满意
He said that you're upset about the air time you're getting.
不是那样的，这不是为了我
That's just wrong, because this is not about me.
我担心的是我们的优先方向
My frustration is with our priorities
以及电视台的最大利益
and what's best for the network.
决定对电台最好的策略 难道不是我的工作吗
Isn't deciding what's best for the network my job?
我只是说
I'm just saying,
作为记者，我们对这个故事有义务
as journalists, we have an obligation to this story.
阿富汗应该暂时多上一些新闻
And Afghanistan should be on our air more, period.
凭借我们在那里的资源
With the resources we have over there,
阿富汗绝对应该多上节目
Afghanistan should definitely be on our air more.
但问题是，只要大家都爱士兵
But the problem is, as much as everyone loves the troops,
他们就不会想再在电视上 看到大兵出现
they don't actually want to watch them on the news anymore.
他们就是不想看
They just don't.
所以我不能给阿富汗更多播出时间
So I can't give Afghanistan more air.
这意味着我需要给阿富汗 更少的资源
Which means I need to give Afghanistan fewer resources.
那才是对台历最好的
That's what's best for the network.
盖里
Geri...
你有个电话
You have that call now.
我不是想当坏人
I'm not trying to be a bitch.
好吧，跟你说件事
Okay, let me pitch you something.
好了，中国矿产让步...
All right, the Chinese mining concession...
天啊
Jesus!
听着，上一个从阿富汗
Look, the last person who got any kind of
得到过消息的人
bounce out of Afghanistan
就是你的朋友谭雅·范德普尔
was your friend Tanya Vanderpoel.
多亏了那个无人机故事 他还帮我摆脱了一个困境
She's actually got me over a barrel thanks to that drone story.
摆脱困境是什么意思
What do you mean, "over a barrel"?
她在伦敦，金姆
She's London, Kim.
- 你要请谭雅 - 对
- You're hiring Tanya. - Yes.
我以为你们是一起飞过来的
I assumed you two flew here together.
她在这
She's here.
对不起，在UAV攻击之前 你就跟她有联系了？
I'm sorry, you started talking to her before the UAV strike?
UAV无人机？
Is UAV a drone?
你好，你去哪？
Hello! Where are you going?
不，我只在这呆几天
No, I'm only here for a few days.
我知道
Oh, I know.
该死
Oh, fuck.
我不知道要跟你说什么
I don't know what to say to you.
对不起，我搞砸了
Ducky, I'm sorry. I fucked up.
你去部落是不是
Did you go to the Tribals
因为要去商量合同？
because you were in a contract negotiation?
伙计，我不会偷走你的工作，好吗
Dude, I'm not stealing your job, okay?
谭雅，这跟我的工作没关系
Tanya, this is not about my fucking job.
我们必须打几个有质量的电话，好吗
We have to make good calls, right?
安迪失去了个眼睛，贾维德死了
And now Andy lost an eye and Jaweed is dead.
天啊，我们都犯过错
Christ, man, we've both fucking made mistakes!
不，告诉我你去部落 不是为了合同
No. Tell me you didn't go to the Tribals because of a contract.
如果贾维德去找你，你会做 跟我完全相同的事
You would have done exactly what I did if Jaweed had gone to you.
不，我不是你
No. I'm not you.
记不记得你第一次外勤？
Do you remember your first embed?
你采访了一个年轻的海军陆战队员？
You interviewed a young Marine?
考夫林？对
Coughlin? Yes. What?
他们播出你的故事后
Yeah, well, after they aired your story,
你用了一小段他说步枪没有上膛的话
where you used his soundbite about not loading his rifle,
他们把他送到赫尔曼德去了
they sent him to Helmand.
他在那被炸断了腿
And he got his legs blown off.
我是这么听说的
So I hear.
喀布尔见
See you in Kabul.
她追踪这个故事我并不感到吃惊
<i>I'm not really surprised she chased the story.</i>
那就是我们的工作 那就是你的工作
That's what we do. That's what you do.
换成我也会去
I would do it.
对不起
Sorry.
该死，我累了
Goddamn it, I'm tired.
你订了回程机票吗
You booked your return yet?
因为如果愿意你可以来格拉斯哥
'Cause you could come through Glasgow if you wanted.
- 我会去找你 - 什么？
<i>- I'll meet you.</i> - What?
不，巴达克山怎么样？
No. What about Badakhshan?
巴达克山，那可以等等
Badakhshan, that will keep
因为该死的山路还被大雪封着
because the fucking pass is still snowed in.
我需要那个故事，我需要 一次成功，好吗
I need that story. I need a hit, all right?
我需要点东西，这样盖里就不会认为
I need something so that Geri doesn't decide
我不如她办公室里那个土耳其恶人有用
I'm more useful as an ottoman in her fucking office.
金姆，你需要的是站在局外看事情
What you need, Kim, is some time out of the bubble.
你最好做好准备，因为我要
<i>You'd better get ready. I'm fucking making love to you</i>
用风笛版的萨德歌曲向你表白
to bagpipe versions of Sade songs.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
真的？你会去格拉斯哥找我？
Really? You'll meet me in Glasgow?
好，我去格拉斯哥
Yeah, I'll meet you in Glasgow.
- 我搭下一班飞机 - 好
<i>- I'll get the next flight.</i> - Okay.
- 拜拜 - 拜拜
- Bye. <i>- Bye.</i>
嘿，安托万
Hey, Antoine.
你从哪来的？ 我还以为你在巴达克山
Where have you come from? I thought you were in Badakhshan.
本来是，连夜飞回来的
I was. Drove back overnight.
等等，什么？通路打开了？
Wait, what? The pass is open?
对，暂时的
<i>Oui.</i> For now.
干杯
Cheers.
天啊
Oh, Christ.
不好意思
Excuse me.
昆都士在附近吗
Kunduz near?
远吗？
Far?
我想租辆车
I'd like to rent a car.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
（达里语）
谢谢
Aye, thank you.
我知道了，多谢
Yeah, I get it. Thank you. Thanks a lot.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
该死
Oh, shit.
（苏格兰格拉斯哥） 欢迎来到格拉斯哥国际机场
<i>Welcome to Glasgow International Airport.</i>
目前室外温度为16摄氏度
<i>Outside temperature's 18 degrees Celsius.</i>
当地时间下午3点
<i>Local time is 15 hours.</i>
将会有空乘协助您取行李
<i>There will be an airline representative to assist you to your luggage.</i>
再次感谢搭乘..
<i>Once again, thank you for flying with us...</i>
（布莱恩：伊安失踪）
天啊
Oh, my God.
（特里：伊安被绑架）
（Br伊安：他的大巴被埋伏）
给苏珊留言
Leaving a message for Susan.
伍德沃德，我又会喀布尔了
Woodward, I'm back in Kabul again.
我想查出些关于
I'm trying to get information about
伊安·麦克凯尔皮消失的消息
the disappearance of Iain MacKelpie,
所以如果路透社有人能帮忙 请回我电话
so if someone at Reuters can please call me back.
收到这条信息请打电话告诉我
Call to let me know that you've received this message.
谢谢
Thank you.
谁会绑架一个苏格兰来的自由摄影师？
Who kidnaps a Scottish freelance photographer?
绑架都是为了钱，对吧？
The whole point of kidnapping is to get money, right?
在我看来
As far as I understand,
伊安只是错误的时间 出现在了错误的地点
Iain was just in the wrong place at the wrong time.
这一团糟的国家现在连 绑架都干不好了吗
Can this half-assed country not even do kidnapping right?
ISAF不认为这是有高度组织的行为
ISAF does not think this was an upper-tier organization.
所以这些人可能会想办法 把他卖给别人
So these men will probably try to sell him to someone else.
然后就要找人聊聊了
And then there will be some talking, you know.
天啊，法希姆，他们会杀了他的
Oh, my God, Fahim. They're gonna kill him.
不，他们不会的
No, they will not, Kim,
听天由命
<i>inshallah.</i>
现在你应该想说“我早说过了”吧
Now is when you're supposed to say "I told you so."
操
Fuck!
斋月结束了，他们在宰羊羔
Ramadan has ended. They are slaughtering lambs.
我能跟他聊聊吗
May I speak with him?
将军很忙
The general's busy.
不是吧？将军？椭圆机？
Really, General? The elliptical?
我膝盖不好
I have bad knees.
你应该不是来这闻汗味的吧
I'm guessing you didn't come here for the smell of balls.
所有人都出去
Everybody get the fuck out!
他们相信他可能被卖给
They believe that he may have been sold
同一区域的
to another organization
另一个组织了
somewhere in that same region.
这个忙有点大，贝克
That's a pretty big ask, Baker.
时间紧迫
There's a real-time clock on this.
对不起，我帮不了你
I'm sorry, I can't help you.
你知道，真可惜
You know, it's just a shame that
你干了这么多高调的事
y'all don't get credit for all these
却没有把功名都揽下来
high-profile things that you do.
特别是外面还有三角洲 和海豹突击队
You know, especially with SEALs and Delta out there.
一星期之后你就没法
I mean, what week goes by that you don't see
在电视上看到那些家伙了，对吗
those assholes on TV, am I right?
然后下一次国会就五角大楼预算投票
And then next time Congress votes on a Pentagon budget
海军陆战队预算又会被小小的 削减10%
and there's this pesky little 10% line item for the Marines,
接下来你们就只能被并入海军了
next thing you know, you guys are just part of the Navy.
不过，长官，你穿着漂亮的白色军装
Although, sir, you would look spectacular
看上去非常帅气
in one of those pretty white uniforms.
天啊，你知道吗
God, you know what?
只是在我看来，和JSOC不同
It's just occurring to me that, unlike JSOC,
你们允许记者随军
you guys allow reporter embeds.
这意味着摄影师能参加战斗任务
Which means that a cameraman could go on a FORECON mission.
你不认为这对军队很好吗，长官
Don't you think that would be great for the Corps, sir?
那种曝光？
That kind of exposure?
对你也挺好的
Pretty good for you, too.
听着，我们不会盲目出击
Look, we don't go in blind.
我们必须知道自己在干什么 要到什么地方去
We have to know what we're doing and where we're going.
这是我们办事的方式
It's the way we work.
我们不太可能得到地址，但是...
We're not likely to get an address, but...
当你有确凿的证据
When you have something concrete,
再回来，我们会马上行动
come back and we'll get kinetic.
噢
Ugh!
请告诉萨迪克先生他的 “特别朋友”来了
Please tell Mr. Sadiq that his "special friend" is here.
我能为你做点什么？泡茶？ 新的PS游戏机？
What can I get for you? Some tea? The new PlayStation?
不，谢谢，我只需要一些你的时间
No, thank you. I just need a moment of your time.
啊
Ah.
我们还是朋友吗，萨迪克
We still friends, Sadiq?
那取决于你，金姆
Well, that is up to you, Kim.
因为你曾经告诉我
Because you once told me
这里发生的事你全都知道
that nothing happens here that you don't know about.
那你一定知道我的朋友
So you must know about my friend.
伊安·麦克凯尔皮被绑架
Iain MacKelpie getting kidnapped.
我听说过，对
I did hear about this, yes.
人人都听说过
Yeah, well, everybody heard about it,
但你这样位高权重的人 肯定真正知道什么
but a powerful man such as yourself must actually know something.
或者你的朋友巴夏·汗 会知道什么
Or your friend Pacha Khan knows something.
或者他的朋友
Or his friend does.
当然
Of course.
我能打听一下，但只能为了
I could make some inquiries, but I can only do this
非常特别的朋友去做
for a very special friend.
我有段视频你应该看看，萨迪克
I have a video that I think you should watch, Sadiq.
按那小三角就行
You push the little triangle.
你能在手机上看视频？
You can watch video on the phone?
这是什么？
What is this?
看上去是阿富汗
It looks like the Attorney General
伊斯兰共和国的司法部长
of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan
在街头
dancing in the street
和伊斯兰的西方敌人
with a Western enemy of Islam
在有酒的派对上跳舞
at a party where alcohol was served.
我这辈子都没碰过酒
I've never touched alcohol in my life!
我只是说这看上去给人的印象
Well, I'm just saying how it looks.
这是个好主意，对吧？
It's a good idea, right?
这是个绝妙的主意
It's a great idea!
简直无敌
It's fucking ace!
干得好，金姆
Good on ya, Kim!
我们走，上飞机，走
Let's go, load up! Let's go, move, move, move!
你喝田纳西威士忌吗，贝克小姐
You drink Tennessee whiskey, Miss Baker?
喝
Yeah.
太棒了
Outstanding.
Br伊安？怎么回事？
Tall Brian? What the fuck?
坐好了，先生，我去帮你叫车
Hang tight, sir. I'm gonna get you that ride.
谢谢
Thank you.
军队怎么了，布莱登医生
What happened to the army, Dr. Brydon?
我就是军队
I am the army.
谢谢，金姆
Thank you, Kim.
你好吗
How are you?
我经历过更惨的绑架
I've had worse kidnappings.
麦克凯尔皮只受了些轻伤
<i>MacKelpie is being treated for minor injuries.</i>
但这些难以置信的视频
<i>Again, this incredible footage</i>
是由我台记者金姆·贝克拍摄
<i>was produced by our very own Kim Baker.</i>
太了不起了，真厉害，金姆
<i>Just incredible. Way to go, Kim!</i>
要是你想绑架一个人两次
If you want to kidnap someone fucking twice,
就得开丰田车
you do a Toyota.
完全没有他们把你从 长袍里拖出来那么有趣
Fucking not as interesting as it got when they fucking pulled out a burqa.
这对我来说太久了
It's too fucking long for me!
我都不知道那是哪个女人的
I don't know who the woman was it belonged to.
我又不是才6英尺2英寸高
I'm not fucking 6'2", right?
我一直拖着这该死的东西 唯一值得安慰的就是
I'm dragging this fucking thing along, thinking the only consolation is,
至少我不是该死的女人
at least if I'm a fucking woman,
我不会被强奸，懂我的意思吗
I'm not gonna get buggered, you know what I'm saying?
总之，我看着就有点那样
So anyway, I took a little something, actually.
我还去了塔利班的礼品店
I went to the gift shop at Taliban.
恐怕我只买到了
I'm afraid all I could get
那些
was that.
- 真可惜你要走了 - 嗯
- It's a shame you're going. - Hmm?
希望他们至少让你坐头等舱
Well, I hope at least they're flying you first class.
盖里没那么喜欢我 但现在她喜欢我了
Geri doesn't like me that much. But she does like me now,
所以，趁我现在还受宠
so while I have this juice,
我得让生活变得更好
I've got to leverage it into something better.
对
Yes!
对，等等，伊拉克
Yes, wait, Iraq.
我跟你一起去
I'll come with you.
不，是巴基斯坦吧 那里到处都是枪声
No, actually, Pakistan. That's where the real shooting shit is.
简直就跟狂野西部一样
It's like the Wild West out there.
实际上，我跟盖里说我想去纽约 或者华盛顿
Actually, I told Geri that I want New York or D.C.
我真的说了
No, I did.
不，你要去哪？
No, really, where are you going?
纽约或者华盛顿
New York or D.C.
为什么？
Why?
你还是可以跟我一起走
You can still come with me.
因为我觉得在现实世界
Because I think there's plenty of good work
还有很多事可以做
to be done in the real world,
而喀布尔现在还不错
and the Kabubble is well-established.
这是为了报复我不带你 一个人去巴达克山吗
Is this about me going to Badakhshan without you?
因为如果是你也会做同样的事
'Cause you would have done exactly the same thing.
嘿，我原谅你
And, hey, what, I forgive you!
这不是因为你
This is not about you.
也不是为了巴达克山或者格拉斯哥
It's not about Badakhshan, or Glasgow,
或者养鸡的小屋
or the cottage with the chickens.
什么鸡
What chickens?
没事，我知道你不会来
It's okay. I know you're not gonna come.
我只是得在一切太迟之前离开这
I just have to get out of here before it's too late.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我开始觉得这都是正常的
I started to feel like this was normal.
你知道这不正常，对吧？
You know it's not, right?
来纽约你就明白
Come to New York and get it.
记住，现在曼哈顿是6点
Remember, you're like a six in Manhattan.
你的孩子怎么样？
How's your baby?
哪个？
Which one?
- 你有两个？ - 对啊
- You have two? - Yes.
爱尔兰双胞胎
Irish twins.
他们都很好
No, they are very good.
小的是男孩，非常有力气
The younger one, the boy, he's very strong.
- 嗯 - 嗯
- Mmm. - Mmm.
女孩肯定也很有力气
I bet the girl is strong, too.
她力气更大
She's stronger.
那么
So, um,
医院那些人，那些成瘾患者...
those men in the hospital, the addicts...
他们中有人好起来了吗？
Any of them ever get better?
有人得到幸福的结局吗？
Have a happy ending?
在我的文化中，我们会拥抱
In my culture, we would hug.
嘿
Hey.
你知道，我怀念阿富汗
<i>You know, I miss it. The Stan.</i>
我也怀念
Yeah, I miss it, too.
实际上我还试过回去
Actually, I tried to go back
但连军队都不肯带我去
but even the Army wouldn't take me.
军队啊，太伤人了
I mean, the Army! I mean, that's just hurtful.
你发生的事我很抱歉
Well, I'm very sorry for what happened to you.
如果有什么你想对我说的
So if there's anything that you want to say to me,
我就是为此而来
that's why I'm here.
我就为这来的
That's why I came here.
女士
Ma'am,
我是因为路边炸弹失去的双腿 不是因为你
I lost my legs because of an IED, not because of you.
谢谢你这么说，但如果不是 我引用你的话
I appreciate that, but if I hadn't quoted you,
你也不会被调走
you wouldn't have been transferred.
不，真的，你想对我说什么都行
No, really, you can say whatever you want to me.
我就是为这来的
That's why I'm here.
好吧，那这么说吧，你是对的
Okay, well, then let's say you're right.
这依然不是因为你，女士
It's still not 'cause of you, ma'am.
一个12岁的教徒安装了那个炸弹
Some 12-year-old haji had to plant that bomb.
你知道，如果本拉登的父母
And, hell, you know, if Bin Laden's parents
没有结婚
hadn't have gotten divorced,
也许我们所有人一开始就不会去那
maybe none of us would've been in the Stan to begin with.
然后塔利班，他们也不会 在那跟UBL打
And the Taliban, they wouldn't have even been there for UBL
要是总统和五角大楼一开始
if Brezhnev hadn't have gone and fouled up Afghanistan
就没在阿富汗捣乱
in the first place.
当然还有大英帝国
And the British Empire. Yeah.
还有金姆·贝克
And Kim Baker.
好吧，我是活该
Okay, I deserve that.
见鬼，你的腿一没了
Goddamn! Once you got no legs,
人人都那么严肃
everyone takes everything so serious.
我们中只有很少的人能稍稍掌控
I mean, there's only so much any of us have any control of,
好或者坏
good or bad.
如果你在阿富汗没学到那些 你就是没认真
If you didn't learn that in Afghanistan, you were not paying attention.
所以你不会冲我大吼大叫？
So, you're not gonna yell at me?
我是说，女士
I mean, ma'am...
金姆，你得走出过去
Kim, you've got to move on.
你给自己揽的负担太多了
You're giving yourself way too much credit.
你拥抱坏事
You embrace the suck,
你得往前走
you move the fuck forward.
我们还有什么选择？
What other fucking choice do we have?
我是不是听到脏话了？
Do I hear swearing over there?
为什么每次我骂人你都会站在边上
How are you standing there the one time I curse?
- 就一次 - 我是说
- "One time." - I mean...
真的，他在军队
It's true. He had a good
一直表现都很好
long run in the military.
别提他打掩护
Don't cover up for him.
那么金姆，你留下吃晚饭吗
So, Kim, are you gonna stay for dinner?
当然了
Of course she will.
再见
Bye!
- 和金姆拜拜，拜拜 - 说拜拜
- Say bye to Kim. Bye, Kim! - Say bye.
上校，阿富汗国民军有错过了
<i>Colonel, the Afghan National Army missed</i>
一个准备的时间节点
<i>yet another benchmark for preparedness.</i>
你认为这对我们从该区域撤军 会产生什么样的影响？
<i>How do you think that will affect our draw down in the region?</i>
我们需要重新审视之前的撤军策略
<i>There needs to be a revision to the previously announced draw down</i>
或者未来的生存战略
<i>or our future exit strategy.</i>
谢谢，罗伯茨上校
<i>Thank you, Colonel Roberts.</i>
谢谢，非常荣幸
<i>Thank you. My pleasure.</i>
接下来，看看发生在
<i>Coming up, a look at the war on terror</i>
我们家园附近的反恐战争 以及那些参战的人们
<i>that's close to home for those of us who cover it.</i>
获奖战地摄影师伊安·麦克凯尔皮
<i>From London, I'll be joined by award-winning</i>
将从伦敦与我们连线
<i>combat photographer, Iain MacKelpie.</i>
他的新书《冲突区》
<i>His new book,</i> Conflict Zone,
记述了他在中东以及阿富汗
<i>chronicles a decade spent working</i>
10年的工作见闻
<i>in the Middle East and Afghanistan.</i>
马上回来
<i>That's when we return.</i>
好的，40秒后回归
<i>And we're clear. Back in 40.</i>
嗨，伊安
<i>Hi, Iain.</i>
嗨，你介绍我的时候
<i>Hi. Was I supposed to say something then</i>
- 我要不要说点什么 - 不
<i>- when you introduced me? - Nope.</i>
不用，坐直了微笑就行
<i>Nope. Just sit up, smile.</i>
我不能笑，笑起来脸上太奇怪了
<i>I can't smile. My face feels weird.</i>
不，没事的，看着不错
<i>No, you're fine. You look good.</i>
谢谢你上节目
<i>Thank you for coming on the show.</i>
不，拜托，谢谢你邀请我
<i>No, please. Thanks for having me.</i>
好了，知道
<i>I got it. Okay, yeah. Got it.</i>
你知道，他们现在给我 安排了个旅行签售
<i>You know, they got me on this book tour at the moment.</i>
我月底会去纽约
<i>I'm gonna be in New York at the end of the month,</i>
要不要一起喝杯咖啡
<i>if you'd fancy a coffee.</i>
恢复播出，5,4,3...
<i>We're back in five, four, three...</i>
（导演：格伦·费卡拉 约翰·雷夸）
字幕由 第三楼字幕网 原创翻译
转载、内封、压制必须注明字幕来源
（主演：蒂娜·菲）
（主演：玛歌特·罗比）
（主演：马丁·弗瑞曼）